<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Life on Colin Sullender</title><link>https://csullender.com/tags/life/</link><description>Recent content in Life on Colin Sullender</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 11:29:44 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csullender.com/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SXSW 2015</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2015/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 02:26:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2015/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another year, another South By, another week of extensive walking and partaking in free parties and concerts. SXSW 2015 has truly turned Austin into a spring break for mid 20-year-olds. As usual, I always go in with zero expectations and just tried to have a good time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first big event was on Saturday at &lt;a href="http://family.do512.com/smartgirlsparty" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amy Poehler&amp;rsquo;s Smart Girls Party&lt;/a> at Banger&amp;rsquo;s Sausage House and Beer Garden which was also where &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/geekandsundry" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Geek &amp;amp; Sundry&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL7atuZxmT956cWFGxqSyRdn6GWhBxiAwE" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tabletop&lt;/a> had all-day events.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Oscar Party 8.0</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/oscar-party-8/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 03:47:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/oscar-party-8/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another year, &lt;a href="https://csullender.com/posts/oscarmadness/" title="#OscarMadness" >another Oscar Party&lt;/a>. The eighth installment of Peter Voyvodic&amp;rsquo;s celebration of the nominees for Academy Award for Best Picture was just as crazy and just as much fun as ever. There&amp;rsquo;s something exhilarating about cramming 50+ people into a tiny studio apartment and preparing an 8-dish offering. The menu and dishes are pictured below. For more behind-the-scenes photos, &lt;a href="https://flic.kr/s/aHsk8Mm9HK" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">check out my Flickr album&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="menu.jpg" alt="Oscar Party VIII Menu">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="the-theory-of-everything">
 The Theory of Everything
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#the-theory-of-everything">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Pork belly with molasses and roasted potatoes with thyme in pea foam&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MotoGP ATX 2014</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/motogp-atx-2014/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 01:28:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/motogp-atx-2014/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="http://www.motogp.com/en/events/Americas/2014" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Red Bull Grand Prix of the Americas&lt;/a> was this past weekend at the &lt;a href="http://circuitoftheamericas.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Circuit of the Americas&lt;/a> in Austin, TX. The event spans three days with practice and qualifiers occurring on Saturday and the races for the three classes (MotoGP, Moto2, and Moto3) occurring on Sunday. I attended both days of weekend events and had a great time watching beastly motorcycles roar past &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/@30.1300364,-97.6369164,252m/data=!3m1!1e3" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Turn 1&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;ve included a selection of photos and videos below. To see all my photos, check out &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/shiruken/sets/72157644000411214/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">my Flickr set&lt;/a>. To see all my videos, check out this &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/PYEuiWbp314?list=PLhmTcup9zvf1WE_QTe0q0G6DrojF6A5rG" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">YouTube playlist&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SXSW 2014</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 00:43:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2014/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another crazy &lt;a href="http://sxsw.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SXSW&lt;/a> has come and gone in Austin, TX, and I&amp;rsquo;m completely exhausted. Unlike the past two years where most of my participation was during the Music portion of the festival, I explored extensively during Interactive (i.e. earlier). The biggest events I attended were the Dropbox party and the multi-day Rachael Ray Feedback House Party. The first was at a brand new bar on Rainey Street called &lt;a href="http://austincontainerbar.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Container Bar&lt;/a> and featured live music from Wild Cub (they&amp;rsquo;re gonna blow up). The second was at an event space on East Cesar Chavez called &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Chick-Ranch-Austin/697801683571177" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chick Ranch&lt;/a> and featured tons of live bands and BBQ from a Chicago restaurant called &lt;a href="http://www.lilliesq.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lillies&lt;/a>. I managed to snag invites to both events for myself and a ton of my friends through some Twitter magic. Besides those, I walked around to a ton of the open venues all across downtown Austin to catch music and eat/drink free stuff. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in seeing my photos, check out &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/shiruken/sets/72157642462282474/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the Flickr set here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#OscarMadness</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/oscarmadness/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 22:23:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/oscarmadness/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the past six years, my friend Peter Voyvodic has hosted an annual Oscar party where he serves up food inspired by each of the Academy Award for Best Picture Nominees. I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to attend the past two years (since I&amp;rsquo;ve been in Austin) and it has always been a blast. Last year I had a ton of fun assisting with the Sunday food preparation so I was anxious to help again this year.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Foursquare Heatmap</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/foursquare-heatmap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 23:06:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/foursquare-heatmap/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m a regular user of the location-based social network &lt;a href="https://foursquare.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Foursquare&lt;/a> mainly as a source of recommendations for new places to try. I typically check in everywhere I go with the exception of private residences (can&amp;rsquo;t let people stalk me that easily), so I have a pretty extensive log covering my location history. While it&amp;rsquo;s not quite as extensive as the &lt;a href="https://maps.google.com/locationhistory/b/0" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Maps Location History&lt;/a>, it does a good job representing the places I visit.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sad Mac: The Chronology of a Broken MacBook Pro</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/sad-mac/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 18:08:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/sad-mac/</guid><description>&lt;p>The following is a record of the problems I encountered with my MacBook Pro (Early 2011) beginning in late August and hopefully culminating in a once-again functional laptop. I&amp;rsquo;m making an effort to document all of the steps I took in attempting to rectify the situation including my experience with the Apple Retail Store. I&amp;rsquo;ve had great experiences with the repair team at Apple Stores in the past and I hope this will continue the trend.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colorado Summer</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/colorado-summer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 23:33:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/colorado-summer/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently visited Estes Park, Colorado where my dad has moved/semi-retired and took a ton of pictures since it&amp;rsquo;s absolutely beautiful up there. Here are a select few with &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/shiruken/sets/72157631087676880/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">many more available&lt;/a> on my Flickr account. Sadly there was almost no snow in the park, which is apparently very unusual (thanks a lot global warming). Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to visit again around Christmas so there should be plenty of that annoying white precipitation on the ground.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Qualifying Exam: Part II</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/the-qualifying-exam-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 15:45:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/the-qualifying-exam-part-ii/</guid><description>&lt;p>As of yesterday afternoon I have completed and passed my qualifying exam for the &lt;a href="https://www.bme.utexas.edu/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Department of Biomedical Engineering&lt;/a> at the &lt;a href="https://www.utexas.edu/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">University of Texas&lt;/a>. As I mentioned in an &lt;a href="https://csullender.com/posts/the-qualifying-exam-part-i/" title="The Qualifying Exam: Part I" >earlier blog post&lt;/a>, the qualifying exam consists of two parts: a written response and an oral exam with a faculty committee. The written part was extremely straightforward and really just required the reading of background papers to adequately answer the questions. More than anything it just served as a starting point for preparing for the oral examination, which is much more open-ended and difficult to predict. All we were told were the time and place of the exam and the number of faculty members that would comprise the committee. There were four in total with two from my research area (Imaging and Instrumentation) and one from each of the other two research areas. Going into the meeting, that was literally the extent of my knowledge concerning the exam, which leaves the mind quite free to imagine horrible, horrible outcomes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Red Bull Battlegrounds</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/red-bull-battlegrounds/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 20:32:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/red-bull-battlegrounds/</guid><description>&lt;p>This past weekend saw the first major competitive video-gaming event take place in Austin, TX as the &lt;a href="http://www.redbullusa.com/cs/Satellite/en_US/Red-Bull-LAN/001243017356310" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Red Bull Battlegrounds&lt;/a> took over the &lt;a href="http://acl-live.com/venue" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Moody Theater&lt;/a> for two days of StarCraft 2 action. A 16-player invitational hosted by Day[9], DJwheat, Husky, and Rob Simpson, the event was a resounding success for a non-major-league (&lt;a href="http://www.majorleaguegaming.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MLG&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="http://www.ign.com/ipl" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">IPL&lt;/a>) live event. I decided to only attend the second day (Sunday) of the tournament since the first day featured a round-robin tournament in which an absolute deluge of games were played. Day 2 took the top 8 players from the previous day and seeded them into a single-elimination bracket to fight for over $40k in prize money.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>M83 Live</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/m83-live/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2012 18:39:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/m83-live/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://ilovem83.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">M83&lt;/a> is absolutely one of my favorite bands to see live. While many people find Anthony Gonzalez&amp;rsquo;s heavily shoegaze-influenced music somewhat boring (excluding that one track that everyone knows from &lt;em>Hurry Up, We&amp;rsquo;re Dreaming&lt;/em>), their live performances are anything but that. From the perfectly implemented light show to the random electronic dance jam sessions in the middle of their more upbeat songs, M83 is a blast to see in concert. Even though there were people at the concert who only wanted to hear &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9aZFcosBTaQ" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Midnight City&lt;/a>,&amp;rdquo; there is no denying that the rest of the show was just as energetic. Their extended versions of &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BFD-dR8ToPM" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fall&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; from the &lt;em>TRON: Legacy&lt;/em> soundtrack and &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wrv0F-WTio4" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Couleurs&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; from &lt;em>Saturdays = Youth&lt;/em> were awesome. Even if you&amp;rsquo;re one of the &amp;ldquo;only likes Midnight City&amp;rdquo; crowd, their live performances make that song look boring in comparison. You should seriously see them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Qualifying Exam: Part I</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/the-qualifying-exam-part-i/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/the-qualifying-exam-part-i/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today marks the beginning of my qualifying exam for becoming a PhD student in &lt;a href="https://www.bme.utexas.edu/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Biomedical Engineering&lt;/a> at the &lt;a href="https://www.utexas.edu/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">University of Texas at Austin&lt;/a>. The exam is taken at the end of the first year of graduate school and basically is a check to make sure that you have the basic research knowledge and critical thinking skills necessary to continue onwards as a doctoral student. The exam is broken into two separate parts: a written exam and an oral exam. Both exams are based off a single research paper, selected by the student depending on their research technical area (I fall within Technical Area #1 - Biomedical Imaging and Instrumentation). Later today I will be given the choice of two different papers to choose from. I will then have to answer five questions regarding the content of the paper, which is due in a week. At some point in the next month I will go before a four-person committee made up of faculty members from each of the different research tracks (Two from my track and one from each of the other two tracks) for an oral exam concerning the paper and more importantly my ability to &amp;ldquo;think on my feet.&amp;rdquo; If all goes well, then I&amp;rsquo;ll be continuing on my way towards getting a PhD in biomedical engineering.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>eSports at SXSW 2012</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/esports-at-sxsw-2012/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 16:12:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/esports-at-sxsw-2012/</guid><description>&lt;p>I went to my first SXSW event this past Saturday (despite the absolute deluge of rain) at the Palmer Event Center for the &lt;a href="http://sxsw.com/interactive/screenburn" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Screenburn Arcade&lt;/a> where the IGN Pro League was putting on a StarCraft 2 showmatch between two community-voted players. Interestingly enough, the players Millenium.Stephano and TteSports.WhiteRa ended up being the winners of the IPL StarLeagues 2 and 3, respectively, which made the match feel even more epic. The Frenchman, Ilyes &amp;ldquo;Stephano&amp;rdquo; Satouri, is arguably the best foreigner (non-Korean) player in the world and definitely one of the best Zerg players globally. Aleksey &amp;ldquo;White-Ra&amp;rdquo; Krupnyk, hails from the Ukraine, and has been a long-time community favorite for his Protoss &amp;ldquo;special tactics&amp;rdquo; and broken English phrases that are frequently absorbed into the StarCraft eSports lexicon. It was awesome seeing these people play in person after being limited to &lt;a href="http://twitch.tv" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TwitchTV&lt;/a> streams and &lt;a href="http://www.majorleaguegaming.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Major League Gaming&lt;/a> events in the past. Nothing beats a live crowd, especially when an &lt;a href="http://wiki.teamliquid.net/starcraft2/Archon_toilet" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Archon Toilet&lt;/a> results in the nearly instantaneous death of 10+ Brood Lords and a complete change in momentum.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fun with Optics</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/fun-with-optics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 23:34:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/fun-with-optics/</guid><description>&lt;p>I spent my entire Saturday helping out at &lt;a href="http://www.utexas.edu/events/exploreut/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Explore UT&lt;/a> as part of a Biomedical Optics Graduate Organization (BOGO) outreach event. We held three forty-minute-long sessions with about thirty kids (8-11 years old) and taught them about optics and the properties of light. Thanks to some incredible funding from our backing organizations (&lt;a href="http://www.osa.org/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OSA&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://spie.org/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SPIE&lt;/a>), we were able to provide the kids with numerous hands-on, take-home demos including polarizers, diffraction gratings, UV color-changing beads, and a telescope. It was great interacting with kids concerning topics that are much more tangible than molecule engineering, which has always been a downside to my previous research experiences. There&amp;rsquo;s just something incredibly satisfying about seeing their eyes light up when they play around with these simple experiments. I think this one picture summarizes everything quite nicely.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Winter in Austin</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/winter-in-austin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 18:09:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/winter-in-austin/</guid><description>&lt;p>This past week has had some absolutely incredible weather, mostly in the upper 70&amp;rsquo;s and mid 80&amp;rsquo;s, but Thursday it decided to dip up into the 90&amp;rsquo;s. After four years of Seattle winters (aka cloudy, cold, and wet), maybe Texas winters aren&amp;rsquo;t all that bad. Sadly it has already dropped back into the mid 60&amp;rsquo;s for the weekend and we might get some thunderstorms early next week. But it&amp;rsquo;s still brilliantly sunny and hopefully indicative of the weather for the next few months. Now if only there was a way to escape the inevitable Texas summer heat.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>