<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Web on Colin Sullender</title><link>https://csullender.com/tags/web/</link><description>Recent content in Web on Colin Sullender</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 16:16:18 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csullender.com/tags/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Migrating Hugo deployment to GitHub Actions from TravisCI</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/migrating-to-github-actions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 14:12:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/migrating-to-github-actions/</guid><description>&lt;p>With the &lt;a href="https://mailchi.mp/3d439eeb1098/travis-ciorg-is-moving-to-travis-cicom" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">recent shutdown of travis-ci.org&lt;/a> and the &lt;a href="https://blog.travis-ci.com/2020-11-02-travis-ci-new-billing" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announcement of a new pricing model&lt;/a> for TravisCI with limited free usage, I made the decision to migrate the CI/CD for this website to &lt;a href="https://github.com/features/actions" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub Actions&lt;/a>. As I mentioned &lt;a href="https://csullender.com/posts/goodbye-wordpress-hello-hugo/" >when I first transitioned to using Hugo&lt;/a>, I&amp;rsquo;m still hosting this website on a paid server to retain a few dynamic pages that would not work properly on a &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/hosting-and-deployment/hosting-on-netlify/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Netlify deployment&lt;/a>. The following are the steps that I took to migrate between services.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Goodbye WordPress. Hello Hugo.</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/goodbye-wordpress-hello-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 12:10:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/goodbye-wordpress-hello-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;p>After eight years of &lt;a href="https://csullender.com/posts/hello-world/" >using WordPress&lt;/a>, I finally decided it&amp;rsquo;s time to rid myself of the &lt;a href="https://www.quora.com/Why-is-WordPress-so-bad-and-are-there-any-real-alternatives" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cumbersome, error-prone beast&lt;/a> in favor of a static website. I rarely post blog entries anymore, so the convenience of the WordPress text editor and dynamic content has lost its appeal, especially since this website now primarily serves as a digital portfolio. After far too much research (i.e. perusing Reddit threads), I decided to use a static site generator to create and maintain the new website.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Three Years of 'Science GIFs' on Google+</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/three-years-of-science-gifs-on-google/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 03:13:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/three-years-of-science-gifs-on-google/</guid><description>&lt;p>Three years ago, Google &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/&amp;#43;googleplus/posts/7ZpGWeou2sV" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced&lt;/a> the Collections feature on the Google+ social network. It offered a way to group posts by topic so that others could follow their specific interests rather than &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/&amp;#43;ColinSullender" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">your entire profile&lt;/a>. I created two collections, &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/collection/MX98P" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Data is Beautiful&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/collection/A2NSc" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Science GIFs&lt;/a>, the latter of which I&amp;rsquo;ve maintained for almost three years now. Every week I post a science-related GIF and an accompanying explanation of the finding, physical phenomenon, or chemical reaction. I try to feature recent research publications and announcements whenever possible to avoid reposting content seen elsewhere online.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reddit and the Death of Stephen Hawking</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/reddit-and-the-death-of-stephen-hawking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 04:46:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/reddit-and-the-death-of-stephen-hawking/</guid><description>&lt;p>As the news of &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-43396008" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Stephen Hawking&amp;rsquo;s death&lt;/a> reverberated across the internet, the &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/science/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">r/science community&lt;/a> on Reddit made an unusual post: &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/84aiy6/physicist_stephen_hawking_dies_aged_76/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">An opportunity to discuss the life of one of humanity&amp;rsquo;s greatest minds&lt;/a>. It was the first post of its kind in a subreddit normally dedicated to talking about science papers. However, the moderator team decided his passing warranted acknowledgement given his contributions to physics and his role as the most widely recognized science communicator on the planet. He had also previously participated in &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/3nyn5i/science_ama_series_stephen_hawking_ama_answers/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an Ask Me Anything&lt;/a> in our subreddit.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Facebook Photo Compression</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/facebook-photo-compression/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 23:11:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/facebook-photo-compression/</guid><description>&lt;script src="https://code.jquery.com/jquery-1.12.4.min.js" integrity="sha256-ZosEbRLbNQzLpnKIkEdrPv7lOy9C27hHQ+Xp8a4MxAQ=" crossorigin="anonymous">&lt;/script>
&lt;script src="https://csullender.com/js/load-photoswipe.js">&lt;/script>


&lt;link rel="stylesheet" href="https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/photoswipe/4.1.1/photoswipe.min.css" integrity="sha256-sCl5PUOGMLfFYctzDW3MtRib0ctyUvI9Qsmq2wXOeBY=" crossorigin="anonymous" />
&lt;link rel="stylesheet" href="https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/photoswipe/4.1.1/default-skin/default-skin.min.css" integrity="sha256-BFeI1V+Vh1Rk37wswuOYn5lsTcaU96hGaI7OUVCLjPc=" crossorigin="anonymous" />
&lt;script src="https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/photoswipe/4.1.1/photoswipe.min.js" integrity="sha256-UplRCs9v4KXVJvVY+p+RSo5Q4ilAUXh7kpjyIP5odyc=" crossorigin="anonymous">&lt;/script>
&lt;script src="https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/photoswipe/4.1.1/photoswipe-ui-default.min.js" integrity="sha256-PWHOlUzc96pMc8ThwRIXPn8yH4NOLu42RQ0b9SpnpFk=" crossorigin="anonymous">&lt;/script>


&lt;div class="pswp" tabindex="-1" role="dialog" aria-hidden="true">

&lt;div class="pswp__bg">&lt;/div>

&lt;div class="pswp__scroll-wrap">
 
 &lt;div class="pswp__container">
 &lt;div class="pswp__item">&lt;/div>
 &lt;div class="pswp__item">&lt;/div>
 &lt;div class="pswp__item">&lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="pswp__ui pswp__ui--hidden">
 &lt;div class="pswp__top-bar">
 
 &lt;div class="pswp__counter">&lt;/div>
 &lt;button class="pswp__button pswp__button--close" title="Close (Esc)">&lt;/button>
 &lt;button class="pswp__button pswp__button--share" title="Share">&lt;/button>
 &lt;button class="pswp__button pswp__button--fs" title="Toggle fullscreen">&lt;/button>
 &lt;button class="pswp__button pswp__button--zoom" title="Zoom in/out">&lt;/button>
 
 
 &lt;div class="pswp__preloader">
 &lt;div class="pswp__preloader__icn">
 &lt;div class="pswp__preloader__cut">
 &lt;div class="pswp__preloader__donut">&lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;div class="pswp__share-modal pswp__share-modal--hidden pswp__single-tap">
 &lt;div class="pswp__share-tooltip">&lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;button class="pswp__button pswp__button--arrow--left" title="Previous (arrow left)">
 &lt;/button>
 &lt;button class="pswp__button pswp__button--arrow--right" title="Next (arrow right)">
 &lt;/button>
 &lt;div class="pswp__caption">
 &lt;div class="pswp__caption__center">&lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>A couple weeks ago there was a &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/android/comments/3mjxz8/tip_if_uploading_images_to_facebook_use/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reddit post on /r/Android&lt;/a> recommending Facebook users upload photos via the &lt;a href="http://m.facebook.com" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">mobile website&lt;/a> rather than the official Android Facebook app. The app reportedly compressed an original 8MP (4.5MB) photo to only 0.6MP (100kB) whereas the mobile website uploaded at 3MP (440kB). For a typical 4:3 ratio photograph, 0.6MP works out to neither dimension having more than 1000 pixels! Viewers on almost all current smartphones and tablets would be looking at an image smaller than their screen size. For a social network so heavily driven by photographs, you would think Facebook would do a better job maintaining some modicum of image quality. Most users probably have no idea their images are being so heavily degraded by uploading via the app. This blog examines the varying quality of Facebook image uploads in an attempt to identify the best option if you must upload to Facebook.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Scholar Visualization</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/google-scholar-visualization/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 16:59:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/google-scholar-visualization/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the most common images I see during science presentations is the frequency of publications within a particular field over time. It&amp;rsquo;s a great way to show the growth of the field while attempting to validate the worthiness of the research that follows. As far as I can tell, most people manually assemble this data with sequential searches on &lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Scholar&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://webofknowledge.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Web of Science&lt;/a>. This seemed like a straightforward opportunity for automation, so &lt;del>I made a little website&lt;/del> (&lt;em>Deprecated July 2022&lt;/em>) that does just that. It takes a Google Scholar search query and a range of years and plots the number of results over time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Full Page Background Image with CSS3</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/full-page-background-image/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 06:08:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/full-page-background-image/</guid><description>&lt;p>Several of the websites I&amp;rsquo;ve created use a background image as part of the design. It turns out that making the image stay centered, maintain the same aspect ratio, scale with the browser, and always fill the entire page is a difficult task. After several infuriating hours of trial and error, I finally figured out how to make all the above occur in a modern browser using only CSS3. &lt;a href="http://jsfiddle.net/o286bbpg/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Check out this JSFiddle&lt;/a> for an example of it in action or read on for an explanation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Taylor Swifting</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/taylor-swifting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 06:28:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/taylor-swifting/</guid><description>&lt;p>I had a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/shiruken/status/536957959503241217" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">really random idea&lt;/a> the other day for a simple coding project using the LastFM API: When was the last time you listened to Taylor Swift? This is obviously an extremely important statistic to know for the Taylor Swift obsessed. I already made a tool to &lt;a href="https://csullender.com/first" >&lt;del>lookup the first time you listened to an artist&lt;/del>&lt;/a> using your LastFM profile, so this was a relatively straightforward adaptation. I also wanted to take this opportunity to leverage the power of &lt;a href="http://jquery.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">jQuery&lt;/a> to asynchronously load the information rather than simply waiting for a static page. Check out &lt;del>The Last Swifting page&lt;/del> (&lt;em>Deprecated July 2022&lt;/em>) or continue reading for more information.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dogecoin Halving Countdown</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/dogecoin-halving-countdown/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 02:07:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/dogecoin-halving-countdown/</guid><description>&lt;p>The first block reward halving for &lt;a href="http://dogecoin.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dogecoin&lt;/a> resulted in many &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/dogecoin/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reddit users&lt;/a> asking when the event was occurring and how much the new block reward would be. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to find a good countdown website so I decided to throw one together myself. It uses the &lt;a href="http://dogechain.info/chain/Dogecoin" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DogeChain&lt;/a> API to grab the current block number and estimates the time until the next change in the block reward. Since the Dogecoin &lt;a href="https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?PHPSESSID=7fsbe1l362dulhpb5an0j4imq0&amp;amp;topic=361813.msg3872945#msg3872945" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">protocol&lt;/a> establishes the specific block rewards, it&amp;rsquo;s relatively simple to calculate it with some accuracy. Check it out by &lt;del>clicking here&lt;/del> &lt;em>(Deprecated July 2022)&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>LastFM First Listen</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/lastfm-first-listen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 03:55:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/lastfm-first-listen/</guid><description>&lt;p>When was the first time you listened to M83? What about LIGHTS? If you&amp;rsquo;re a &lt;a href="http://www.last.fm/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LastFM&lt;/a> user, then I&amp;rsquo;ve made a &lt;del>little web-app&lt;/del> (&lt;em>Deprecated July 2022&lt;/em>) you can use to look it up! All you need is an active LastFM account and to have been tracking your music listening with their scrobbling service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="M83First.jpg" alt="First Time I Listened to M83">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All you need to do is enter any LastFM username and artist and then hit submit. The website uses the LastFM &lt;code>user.getArtistTracks&lt;/code> API method to fetch every single track the user has scrobbled from that particular artist. The XML returned file is segmented into 50 plays-per-page but fortunately reports the total number of pages in the first child element. This number is used to jump to the last page of the data, which contains the very first scrobbled track by the user for the particular artist. From there it&amp;rsquo;s just a matter of parsing the XML structure and grabbing the necessary information for display on the webpage with PHP.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Twitter Analytics 2.0</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/twitter-analytics-2-0/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 22:07:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/twitter-analytics-2-0/</guid><description>&lt;p>A couple years ago I made a simple Twitter Stats page to depict my tweeting activity. It was originally powered by some datasets pulled from &lt;a href="http://www.tweetstats.com/" title="Visit Tweetstats" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TweetStats&lt;/a> but I eventually upgraded it to run entirely from my own server. It was extremely barebones and grabbed my &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/shiruken" title="View My Twitter" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Twitter&lt;/a> feed every hour and downloaded all the tweets that had been added since the previous update. Unfortunately, because Twitter does not offer the entire tweeting history via the website or this XML feed, I was missing well over a year of data. Combined with problems accessing this feed, I would regularly lose my entire (local) cache of my Twitter feed and have to spend a lot of time fixing everything. I eventually just decided to kill off the page since I was losing more and more of the older tweets every time I had to fix the cache and Twitter was changing the way the feed was presented.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Website Crafting for BOGO</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/website-crafting-for-bogo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 03:36:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/website-crafting-for-bogo/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the student groups I&amp;rsquo;m involved in at the University of Texas is the &lt;a href="http://studentorgs.engr.utexas.edu/bogo" title="BOGO Website" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Biomedical Optics Graduate Organization&lt;/a> (BOGO). We&amp;rsquo;ve recently had some changes in the leadership and I&amp;rsquo;m now the Treasurer for the group. One of the tasks I decided to undertake was an updated website that keeps better track of our upcoming events as well as helping members announce their publications and achievements. Unfortunately the webspace we&amp;rsquo;re provided by UT is very limited and pretty much can only allow for static webpages (sadly cannot use Wordpress). I spent a few hours throwing together the new design and making it as &lt;em>easy&lt;/em> as possible for future updating of content. Fortunately PHP is available so some of the more frustrating things to update (i.e. the list of members displayed in a table) can be automatically generated from a list of the users. I&amp;rsquo;ve also opted to use Google Calendar and Google Drive to provide functionality on the website in the form of our future events list and contact form. We&amp;rsquo;ve had some trouble in the past with incoming emails getting lost in our mailing list, so hopefully the new contact options will help alleviate that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Here We Go Again</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/here-we-go-again/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2012 05:59:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/here-we-go-again/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well, it&amp;rsquo;s that time of year again when I randomly and decisively to completely redesign my website. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to abandon the automatically generated &lt;a href="http://flavors.me/shiruken" title="View My Flavors.me Profile" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Flavors.me profile&lt;/a> in favor of a more versatile Wordpress installation (again). I&amp;rsquo;m planning on making the front page a mostly static representation of my real life identity and relying on a few widgets along the bottom to cover some of my more frequently utilized social networks (Twitter and Flickr right now). Of course, I&amp;rsquo;ll be linking to all the other ones on a separate page or maybe throwing together an aggregate page á la Flavors.me style. Wordpress will also make my planned return to blogging considerably easier (because I really need to ramble online some more). The state of this website will probably be in flux for quite a while since I have to juggle school and work amongst other things to tinker with it, but definitely keep an eye out for some content here in the future. Happy Interneting!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>