<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Colin Sullender</title><link>https://csullender.com/</link><description>Recent content on Colin Sullender</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 15:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csullender.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Scholar Plotr</title><link>https://csullender.com/scholar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/scholar/</guid><description>Because of anti-scraping protections implemented by Google, the Scholar Plotr tool no longer reliably functions and has been deprecated. A similar visualization can be obtained using the Dimensions platform, although the results are more limited and the underlying data is not made available.
Check out my other coding projects.</description></item><item><title>Tracking Broken Water Pipes in Austin, TX</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/tracking-broken-water-pipes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/tracking-broken-water-pipes/</guid><description>A massive winter storm in February disrupted power generation across the state of Texas and caused nearly 3 million households to lose electricity. As Austin Energy struggled to implement rolling blackouts to reduce energy demand, many neighborhoods in the city went multiple days without electricity during record-breaking cold weather. With residents suddenly unable to heat their homes, Austin and Travis County emergency services were flooded with calls about broken water pipes.</description></item><item><title>Artists I've Seen Live</title><link>https://csullender.com/live-music/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 10:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/live-music/</guid><description>An incomplete list of artists that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen live in concert. For more detail, see my Concert Archives profile.
...And You Will Know Us by the Trail of Dead A Bullet for Pretty Boy A Place to Bury Strangers A Silent Film Abandon All Ships Acid Dad Aero Flynn Against Me! Alberta Cross Alesana Alice Phoebe Lou Amaru Tribe Amateur Radio Operator Anberlin And the Kids Apocalyptica Arcade Fire Arlie Asking Alexandria Augustana Autovaughn Balance and Composure Band of Skulls Ben Kweller Ben Sollee Best Coast Black Tabs Blank Range Blitzen Trapper Blue Light Curtain Blue Scholars Blue Sky Riders Bob Schneider boots Boy Azooga Boy Scouts Brickwaller Bright Eyes Broncho Bronze Fawn Built to Spill Capgun Coup Carrie Rodriguez Castlecomer Charli XCX Cheerleader Cheers Elephant Chiodos CHVRCHES Circa Survive Close to Home Cobra Starship Coheed and Cambria Cold Fronts Colony House Conditions Confide Copy Cotillon Crocodiles Daddy Issues Dance Gavin Dance Deep State Delta Spirit Diarrhea Planet Disclosure Displace Durand Jones &amp;amp; The Indications D∆WN Eagles of Death Metal Eisley Elliot Jacobson Emery Emily Estefan Eminence Ensemble Emmure Envy on the Coast Evergreen Terrace Family Force 5 Family of the Year Flint Eastwood Fly Golden Eagle Foxy Shazam From First to Last Funeral for a Friend Future Teens G.</description></item><item><title>Migrating Hugo deployment to GitHub Actions from TravisCI</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/migrating-to-github-actions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 14:12:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/migrating-to-github-actions/</guid><description>With the recent shutdown of travis-ci.org and the announcement of a new pricing model for TravisCI with limited free usage, I made the decision to migrate the CI/CD for this website to GitHub Actions. As I mentioned when I first transitioned to using Hugo, I&amp;rsquo;m still hosting this website on a paid server to retain a few dynamic pages that would not work properly on a Netlify deployment. The following are the steps that I took to migrate between services.</description></item><item><title>Goodbye WordPress. Hello Hugo.</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/goodbye-wordpress-hello-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 12:10:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/goodbye-wordpress-hello-hugo/</guid><description>After eight years of using WordPress, I finally decided it&amp;rsquo;s time to rid myself of the cumbersome, error-prone beast in favor of a static website. I rarely post blog entries anymore, so the convenience of the WordPress text editor and dynamic content has lost its appeal, especially since this website now primarily serves as a digital portfolio. After far too much research (i.e. perusing Reddit threads), I decided to use a static site generator to create and maintain the new website.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://csullender.com/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 20:33:46 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/about/</guid><description>My name is Colin Sullender and I am a postdoctoral researcher at the University of Texas in Austin specializing in optical system design and digital image processing for biomedical applications. I earned my doctorate and master&amp;rsquo;s from the University of Texas in Austin and attended the University of Washington in Seattle for my undergraduate studies. I was born and raised in Homewood, Alabama.
This website serves as a digital portfolio and mostly inactive blog.</description></item><item><title>Three Years of 'Science GIFs' on Google+</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/three-years-of-science-gifs-on-google/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 03:13:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/three-years-of-science-gifs-on-google/</guid><description>Three years ago, Google announced the Collections feature on the Google+ social network. It offered a way to group posts by topic so that others could follow their specific interests rather than your entire profile. I created two collections, Data is Beautiful and Science GIFs, the latter of which I&amp;rsquo;ve maintained for almost three years now. Every week I post a science-related GIF and an accompanying explanation of the finding, physical phenomenon, or chemical reaction.</description></item><item><title>Reddit and the Death of Stephen Hawking</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/reddit-and-the-death-of-stephen-hawking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 04:46:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/reddit-and-the-death-of-stephen-hawking/</guid><description>As the news of Stephen Hawking&amp;rsquo;s death reverberated across the internet, the r/science community on Reddit made an unusual post: An opportunity to discuss the life of one of humanity&amp;rsquo;s greatest minds. It was the first post of its kind in a subreddit normally dedicated to talking about science papers. However, the moderator team decided his passing warranted acknowledgement given his contributions to physics and his role as the most widely recognized science communicator on the planet.</description></item><item><title>Websites</title><link>https://csullender.com/websites/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 05:25:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/websites/</guid><description>Add me on LinkedIn and GitHub. Check out my coding projects.
Reddit r/science (2015 - Current) Link to heading reddit.com/r/science
The r/science community on Reddit is the largest science discussion platform on the internet with over 23 million subscribers and tens of millions of monthly pageviews. As a lead moderator of this subreddit, I help establish community policy and guide scientific discourse. Our Ask Me Anything and Science Discussion series have hosted hundreds of scientists, engineers, doctors, and other experts to discuss their current work with a more general audience.</description></item><item><title>Goodbye BitTorrent Sync. Hello Syncthing.</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/goodbye-bittorrent-sync-hello-syncthing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 19:26:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/goodbye-bittorrent-sync-hello-syncthing/</guid><description>I first started using BitTorrent Sync back during its Alpha release in early 2013 as an alternative to Dropbox for syncing large quantities of files across my work computers. I needed an easy way to automatically transfer data from my collection computer to the lab server for storage and to my office computer for post-processing. While I have much more free storage than your average non-paying Dropbox user, I needed to regularly transfer tens of gigabytes of files without any need of uploading to the Internet/cloud.</description></item><item><title>Facebook Photo Compression</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/facebook-photo-compression/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 23:11:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/facebook-photo-compression/</guid><description>A couple weeks ago there was a Reddit post on /r/Android recommending Facebook users upload photos via the mobile website rather than the official Android Facebook app. The app reportedly compressed an original 8MP (4.5MB) photo to only 0.6MP (100kB) whereas the mobile website uploaded at 3MP (440kB). For a typical 4:3 ratio photograph, 0.6MP works out to neither dimension having more than 1000 pixels! Viewers on almost all current smartphones and tablets would be looking at an image smaller than their screen size.</description></item><item><title>SXSW 2015</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2015/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 02:26:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2015/</guid><description>Another year, another South By, another week of extensive walking and partaking in free parties and concerts. SXSW 2015 has truly turned Austin into a spring break for mid 20-year-olds. As usual, I always go in with zero expectations and just tried to have a good time.
The first big event was on Saturday at Amy Poehler&amp;rsquo;s Smart Girls Party at Banger&amp;rsquo;s Sausage House and Beer Garden which was also where Geek &amp;amp; Sundry and Tabletop had all-day events.</description></item><item><title>Hackintosh 2.0 Benchmark</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/hackintosh-2.0-benchmark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 21:37:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/hackintosh-2.0-benchmark/</guid><description>Since I am obsessed with quantifying things, I absolutely had to benchmark my new Hackintosh rig to see what my new purchases had afforded cost me. I ran a handful of different benchmarks under both OS X and Windows boots to see what the Intel Core i5-4690K, EVGA GeForce GTX 970 SC, and Samsung 850 Pro could do. So without further ado, here are the results of my benchmarks!
Geekbench Link to heading Tested processor performance across Hackintosh v1.</description></item><item><title>Oscar Party 8.0</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/oscar-party-8/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 03:47:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/oscar-party-8/</guid><description>Another year, another Oscar Party. The eighth installment of Peter Voyvodic&amp;rsquo;s celebration of the nominees for Academy Award for Best Picture was just as crazy and just as much fun as ever. There&amp;rsquo;s something exhilarating about cramming 50+ people into a tiny studio apartment and preparing an 8-dish offering. The menu and dishes are pictured below. For more behind-the-scenes photos, check out my Flickr album.
The Theory of Everything Link to heading Pork belly with molasses and roasted potatoes with thyme in pea foam</description></item><item><title>Hackintosh 2.0</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/hackintosh-2.0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 04:58:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/hackintosh-2.0/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been roughly two years since I built my original Hackintosh desktop computer and I decided earlier this year that the time was ripe for an upgrade. After considerable waffling on the exact components to get, I finally settled on an relatively high-end build largely based on the December CustoMac Buyer&amp;rsquo;s Guide that reused a few components from my original Hackintosh (case, power supply, and memory).
Gigabyte GA-Z97X-UD5H (Motherboard) Intel Core i5-4690K (CPU) EVGA GeForce GTX 970 Superclocked (GPU) Samsung 850 Pro SSD 256GB (SSD) TP-Link PCI Express Wifi Adapter (WiFi) The most difficult decision by far concerned the graphics card since the current generation Mac Pro uses a custom AMD GPU whereas most Hackintosh guides recommend NVIDIA cards.</description></item><item><title>Google Scholar Visualization</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/google-scholar-visualization/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 16:59:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/google-scholar-visualization/</guid><description>One of the most common images I see during science presentations is the frequency of publications within a particular field over time. It&amp;rsquo;s a great way to show the growth of the field while attempting to validate the worthiness of the research that follows. As far as I can tell, most people manually assemble this data with sequential searches on Google Scholar or Web of Science. This seemed like a straightforward opportunity for automation, so I made a little website (Deprecated July 2022) that does just that.</description></item><item><title>Full Page Background Image with CSS3</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/full-page-background-image/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 06:08:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/full-page-background-image/</guid><description>Several of the websites I&amp;rsquo;ve created use a background image as part of the design. It turns out that making the image stay centered, maintain the same aspect ratio, scale with the browser, and always fill the entire page is a difficult task. After several infuriating hours of trial and error, I finally figured out how to make all the above occur in a modern browser using only CSS3. Check out this JSFiddle for an example of it in action or read on for an explanation.</description></item><item><title>Taylor Swifting</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/taylor-swifting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 06:28:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/taylor-swifting/</guid><description>I had a really random idea the other day for a simple coding project using the LastFM API: When was the last time you listened to Taylor Swift? This is obviously an extremely important statistic to know for the Taylor Swift obsessed. I already made a tool to lookup the first time you listened to an artist using your LastFM profile, so this was a relatively straightforward adaptation. I also wanted to take this opportunity to leverage the power of jQuery to asynchronously load the information rather than simply waiting for a static page.</description></item><item><title>Half a Year with Dash</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/half-a-year-with-dash/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2014 20:48:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/half-a-year-with-dash/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Dash in my car for almost six months now to track my driving habits and monitor my car&amp;rsquo;s status. The app interfaces over Bluetooth with an OBD device to read engine codes and access metrics such as speed, fuel efficiency, and engine status. The app tracks every trip and assigns a &amp;ldquo;Driving Score&amp;rdquo; based on driving behavior to encourage &amp;ldquo;better&amp;rdquo; driving habits. Currently the only way to access the data is via an IFTTT channel that logs each trip to a line of a Google Spreadsheet.</description></item><item><title>Automatic Android Location Mode Toggling 2.0</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/automatic-android-location-mode-toggling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 16:14:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/automatic-android-location-mode-toggling/</guid><description>A few months ago I had a blog post about automatically toggling Android Location Mode on my smartphone between High Accuracy and Battery Saving when using certain apps. Using the super-app Tasker and a 3rd-party plugin called Secure Settings I was able to swap the Location Mode of my Nexus 5 between the two modes. However, this was a poor solution since closing an app would result in disabling GPS access, which was undesirable if navigation was currently active.</description></item><item><title>Coding</title><link>https://csullender.com/coding/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 16:30:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/coding/</guid><description>Add me on LinkedIn and GitHub. Check out my websites.
Reddit r/science DOI Checker Link to heading Automatic digital object identifier (DOI) lookup for posts on the r/science community used to facilitate the moderation of reposts and other invalid submissions. Powered by PRAW using Beautiful Soup for parsing website content and Flask for generating the frontend interface. Hosted using Oracle Cloud Free Tier.
Texas COVID-19 Vaccine Tracker Link to heading covid-texas.</description></item><item><title>MotoGP ATX 2014</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/motogp-atx-2014/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 01:28:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/motogp-atx-2014/</guid><description>The Red Bull Grand Prix of the Americas was this past weekend at the Circuit of the Americas in Austin, TX. The event spans three days with practice and qualifiers occurring on Saturday and the races for the three classes (MotoGP, Moto2, and Moto3) occurring on Sunday. I attended both days of weekend events and had a great time watching beastly motorcycles roar past Turn 1. I&amp;rsquo;ve included a selection of photos and videos below.</description></item><item><title>SXSW 2014</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 00:43:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2014/</guid><description>Another crazy SXSW has come and gone in Austin, TX, and I&amp;rsquo;m completely exhausted. Unlike the past two years where most of my participation was during the Music portion of the festival, I explored extensively during Interactive (i.e. earlier). The biggest events I attended were the Dropbox party and the multi-day Rachael Ray Feedback House Party. The first was at a brand new bar on Rainey Street called Container Bar and featured live music from Wild Cub (they&amp;rsquo;re gonna blow up).</description></item><item><title>#OscarMadness</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/oscarmadness/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 22:23:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/oscarmadness/</guid><description>For the past six years, my friend Peter Voyvodic has hosted an annual Oscar party where he serves up food inspired by each of the Academy Award for Best Picture Nominees. I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to attend the past two years (since I&amp;rsquo;ve been in Austin) and it has always been a blast. Last year I had a ton of fun assisting with the Sunday food preparation so I was anxious to help again this year.</description></item><item><title>Support Dogecoin with Facebook Timeline Cover Images!</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/support-dogecoin-with-facebook-timeline-cover-images/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 22:37:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/support-dogecoin-with-facebook-timeline-cover-images/</guid><description>I made a few Dogecoin-themed Facebook timeline cover images during a contest on Reddit last week. I wanted to create more minimalistic images rather than the extremely busy/stylized images other contestants were presenting. I also wanted to steer away from the Comic Sans MS and Doge-speak in favor of a more serious look. The resulting images are displayed below along with a Facebook demo and anyone is welcome to use them on Facebook (or elsewhere) to show their support for Dogecoin.</description></item><item><title>Dogecoin Halving Countdown</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/dogecoin-halving-countdown/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 02:07:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/dogecoin-halving-countdown/</guid><description>The first block reward halving for Dogecoin resulted in many Reddit users asking when the event was occurring and how much the new block reward would be. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to find a good countdown website so I decided to throw one together myself. It uses the DogeChain API to grab the current block number and estimates the time until the next change in the block reward. Since the Dogecoin protocol establishes the specific block rewards, it&amp;rsquo;s relatively simple to calculate it with some accuracy.</description></item><item><title>Automatically Toggle 'High Accuracy' Location Mode on Android</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/automatic-high-accuracy-android-location/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 22:53:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/automatic-high-accuracy-android-location/</guid><description>Check out this blog post for an updated Android Location Mode toggling task
One of Android&amp;rsquo;s most innovative features is Google Now, a service that attempts to provide relevant information to the user based on location and time. Unfortunately, in order to utilize the location-based service, your smartphone must provide location information to Google at expense of battery life. When Android 4.4 &amp;ldquo;Kitkat&amp;rdquo; was released in late October, the location settings were updated to include three different modes: High accuracy, battery saving, and device only.</description></item><item><title>Quickstart Dogecoin blockchain sync with bootstrap.dat</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/quickstart-dogecoin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 01:00:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/quickstart-dogecoin/</guid><description>While Bitcoin is the undisputed leader of the cryptocurrency world, a meme-based alternative called Dogecoin has gained steam over the past month. Sporting the comical Shiba Inu dog character from the &amp;ldquo;doge&amp;rdquo; meme, this altcoin gained significant media coverage recently after helping raise $30,000 for the Jamaican bobsled team for the 2014 Sochi Winter Olympics. Promoters of this cryptocurrency have been extremely vocal about the carefree attitude surrounding Dogecoin and actively encourage giving freely to others (tipping) in order to raise awareness.</description></item><item><title>Get the Price of Bitcoin with Google Now</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/google-now-bitcoin-price/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 00:31:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/google-now-bitcoin-price/</guid><description>The digital currency Bitcoin has grown increasingly popular in recent months as more and more businesses have begun accepting the peer-to-peer cryptocurrency. Keeping up with the highly volatile price of Bitcion (BTC) is a must for traders, who use exchanges such as Mt.Gox or BTC-E to turn a profit. Even the casual holder through services such as Coinbase need to see how much their BTC are worth. While there are many websites that track the price of BTC across exchanges, there is no official integration into Google&amp;rsquo;s search engine.</description></item><item><title>Top Music of 2013</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/top-music-of-2013/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 23:35:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/top-music-of-2013/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m really bad at picking my favorite music of the year, so I&amp;rsquo;ll let the LastFM audioscrobbler do it for me. I figure I listen to whatever I like the most, so it should more or less be representative of my picks for the year. What follows are my favorite albums and artists of the year based on playcounts!
Top 10 Albums of 2013 Link to heading CHVRCHES - The Bones of What You Believe</description></item><item><title>Foursquare Heatmap</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/foursquare-heatmap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 23:06:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/foursquare-heatmap/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a regular user of the location-based social network Foursquare mainly as a source of recommendations for new places to try. I typically check in everywhere I go with the exception of private residences (can&amp;rsquo;t let people stalk me that easily), so I have a pretty extensive log covering my location history. While it&amp;rsquo;s not quite as extensive as the Google Maps Location History, it does a good job representing the places I visit.</description></item><item><title>200k LastFM Scrobbles</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/200k-lastfm-scrobbles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 20:25:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/200k-lastfm-scrobbles/</guid><description>I recently surpassed the 200,000 song scrobble mark on LastFM since joining way back in March 2005. I threw together a little infographic summarizing my overall top artists, albums, and songs over the past 8+ years. I&amp;rsquo;m going to make a yearly summary so that all my charts aren&amp;rsquo;t overwhelmed by the stuff I listened to back in high school. Click on the image for the full-sized infographic. Everything was created in Adobe Illustrator using information and images from the LastFM website.</description></item><item><title>HaloTV Archive</title><link>https://csullender.com/halotv/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 23:21:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/halotv/</guid><description>I used to help run a website back in the day called HaloTV where we hosted tons of Halo videos. There were montages, many of the original Halo machinima videos (Red vs. Blue, Codex, Fire Team Charlie, etc.), and all sorts of trick videos. It was fun times.
I&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded the entire ~10GB of videos to Google Drive to share (also embedded below).
Happy reminiscing Reclaimer!</description></item><item><title>3 Months of Fitbit</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/3-months-of-fitbit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 23:31:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/3-months-of-fitbit/</guid><description>I bought myself a Fitbit One right before the New Year in hopes of motivating more physical activity to offset my stationary lab lifestyle. It&amp;rsquo;s been just over three months since I started tracking my daily steps and most of my sleep. While I haven&amp;rsquo;t started running yet (I promise I&amp;rsquo;ll start eventually), it&amp;rsquo;s been fascinating to see my walking activity tracked throughout the day. One of my biggest complaints about Fitbit&amp;rsquo;s services is that they make you pay to access in-depth information about your activity.</description></item><item><title>LastFM First Listen</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/lastfm-first-listen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 03:55:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/lastfm-first-listen/</guid><description>When was the first time you listened to M83? What about LIGHTS? If you&amp;rsquo;re a LastFM user, then I&amp;rsquo;ve made a little web-app (Deprecated July 2022) you can use to look it up! All you need is an active LastFM account and to have been tracking your music listening with their scrobbling service.
All you need to do is enter any LastFM username and artist and then hit submit. The website uses the LastFM user.</description></item><item><title>Twitter Analytics 2.0</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/twitter-analytics-2-0/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 22:07:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/twitter-analytics-2-0/</guid><description>A couple years ago I made a simple Twitter Stats page to depict my tweeting activity. It was originally powered by some datasets pulled from TweetStats but I eventually upgraded it to run entirely from my own server. It was extremely barebones and grabbed my Twitter feed every hour and downloaded all the tweets that had been added since the previous update. Unfortunately, because Twitter does not offer the entire tweeting history via the website or this XML feed, I was missing well over a year of data.</description></item><item><title>Fixing a Broken Google Wallet</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/fixing-a-broken-google-wallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 03:06:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/fixing-a-broken-google-wallet/</guid><description>I recently upgraded to a Google Nexus 4 phone from my old HTC Inspire HD. Unfortunately, the original device that I received had some problems with the ear-piece, resulting in a very noticeable static hissing noise during calls and even when the phone wasn&amp;rsquo;t in use. I decided to RMA the defective device to Google in exchange for a replacement. After several weeks of waiting, I finally got my hands on my Rev.</description></item><item><title>Keeping your Papers Library Synced</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/papers-sync/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:32:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/papers-sync/</guid><description>As a graduate student, one of the most important tools I use practically every single day is a citation and bibliography reference manager. I&amp;rsquo;ve gone through several (Endnote, Mendeley, Zotero, etc.) over the years before finding one I truly liked: Papers. Initially a Mac-only client, Papers seemed like a native extension of the OS X environment, akin to that of iTunes or iPhoto. With the ability to search online databases, import articles into a &amp;ldquo;library&amp;rdquo; for organization, and cite papers and assemble bibliographies, Papers does everything I needed and wanted from a reference management program.</description></item><item><title>Prevent Bootcamp Partition from Mounting</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/prevent-bootcamp-partition-from-automatically-mounting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 04:34:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/prevent-bootcamp-partition-from-automatically-mounting/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re on a Mac with Windows installed via Bootcamp then you&amp;rsquo;ve no doubt noticed that the Bootcamp partition mounts as another drive when using OSX. I rarely needed access to the contents of my Bootcamp installation so I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be nice to prevent the partition from mounting at all on the Mac side of things. There&amp;rsquo;s a relatively easy way to achieve this using just a little bit of command line fiddling.</description></item><item><title>Website Crafting for BOGO</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/website-crafting-for-bogo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 03:36:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/website-crafting-for-bogo/</guid><description>One of the student groups I&amp;rsquo;m involved in at the University of Texas is the Biomedical Optics Graduate Organization (BOGO). We&amp;rsquo;ve recently had some changes in the leadership and I&amp;rsquo;m now the Treasurer for the group. One of the tasks I decided to undertake was an updated website that keeps better track of our upcoming events as well as helping members announce their publications and achievements. Unfortunately the webspace we&amp;rsquo;re provided by UT is very limited and pretty much can only allow for static webpages (sadly cannot use Wordpress).</description></item><item><title>Sad Mac: The Chronology of a Broken MacBook Pro</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/sad-mac/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 18:08:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/sad-mac/</guid><description>The following is a record of the problems I encountered with my MacBook Pro (Early 2011) beginning in late August and hopefully culminating in a once-again functional laptop. I&amp;rsquo;m making an effort to document all of the steps I took in attempting to rectify the situation including my experience with the Apple Retail Store. I&amp;rsquo;ve had great experiences with the repair team at Apple Stores in the past and I hope this will continue the trend.</description></item><item><title>Colorado Summer</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/colorado-summer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 23:33:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/colorado-summer/</guid><description>I recently visited Estes Park, Colorado where my dad has moved/semi-retired and took a ton of pictures since it&amp;rsquo;s absolutely beautiful up there. Here are a select few with many more available on my Flickr account. Sadly there was almost no snow in the park, which is apparently very unusual (thanks a lot global warming). Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to visit again around Christmas so there should be plenty of that annoying white precipitation on the ground.</description></item><item><title>Getting MATLAB to work on Mac OS X 10.8 'Mountain Lion'</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/getting-matlab-to-work-in-mountain-lion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 15:36:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/getting-matlab-to-work-in-mountain-lion/</guid><description>One of the biggest risks of immediately upgrading to a new operating system is the loss of functionality for vital programs. While developers will scramble to get their apps ready for the sweeping changes oft accompanied by an upgrade to an operating system, it is inevitable that bugs/quirks/errors will surface. As an engineering graduate student, one of the programs I use quite frequently is MATLAB, which is built upon the X11 window system for the Apple OS environment.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading to Mountain Lion</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/upgrading-to-mountain-lion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 19:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/upgrading-to-mountain-lion/</guid><description>The release of the latest Apple computer operating system OS X 10.8 &amp;lsquo;Mountain Lion&amp;rsquo; has been a resounding success with over 3 million copies sold in less than four days. As with any system update, the Hackintosh community anxiously starts refreshing their favorite websites (TonyMacx86) in hopes of reading tales of successful installations before attempting it themselves. After installing the $20 update onto my laptop, I finally decided to give it a whirl on my Hackintosh.</description></item><item><title>The Darkness over the Dark Knight</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/the-darkness-over-the-dark-knight/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 23:17:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/the-darkness-over-the-dark-knight/</guid><description>As I&amp;rsquo;m sure everyone online already knows, tragedy struck Aurora, Colorado early on Friday morning at a midnight showing of Christopher Nolan&amp;rsquo;s final installment in the Batman franchise. Twelve people lost their lives and over fifty were treated for injuries received during the assault. My thoughts go out to the family members, friends, and residents of Aurora and Denver whose lives were devastated by this senseless violence. I threw together a quick image for use as an avatar or a Facebook Timeline cover that features the Batman symbol.</description></item><item><title>The Qualifying Exam: Part II</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/the-qualifying-exam-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 15:45:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/the-qualifying-exam-part-ii/</guid><description>As of yesterday afternoon I have completed and passed my qualifying exam for the Department of Biomedical Engineering at the University of Texas. As I mentioned in an earlier blog post, the qualifying exam consists of two parts: a written response and an oral exam with a faculty committee. The written part was extremely straightforward and really just required the reading of background papers to adequately answer the questions. More than anything it just served as a starting point for preparing for the oral examination, which is much more open-ended and difficult to predict.</description></item><item><title>Red Bull Battlegrounds</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/red-bull-battlegrounds/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 20:32:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/red-bull-battlegrounds/</guid><description>This past weekend saw the first major competitive video-gaming event take place in Austin, TX as the Red Bull Battlegrounds took over the Moody Theater for two days of StarCraft 2 action. A 16-player invitational hosted by Day[9], DJwheat, Husky, and Rob Simpson, the event was a resounding success for a non-major-league (MLG or IPL) live event. I decided to only attend the second day (Sunday) of the tournament since the first day featured a round-robin tournament in which an absolute deluge of games were played.</description></item><item><title>M83 Live</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/m83-live/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2012 18:39:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/m83-live/</guid><description>M83 is absolutely one of my favorite bands to see live. While many people find Anthony Gonzalez&amp;rsquo;s heavily shoegaze-influenced music somewhat boring (excluding that one track that everyone knows from Hurry Up, We&amp;rsquo;re Dreaming), their live performances are anything but that. From the perfectly implemented light show to the random electronic dance jam sessions in the middle of their more upbeat songs, M83 is a blast to see in concert. Even though there were people at the concert who only wanted to hear &amp;ldquo;Midnight City,&amp;rdquo; there is no denying that the rest of the show was just as energetic.</description></item><item><title>The Qualifying Exam: Part I</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/the-qualifying-exam-part-i/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/the-qualifying-exam-part-i/</guid><description>Today marks the beginning of my qualifying exam for becoming a PhD student in Biomedical Engineering at the University of Texas at Austin. The exam is taken at the end of the first year of graduate school and basically is a check to make sure that you have the basic research knowledge and critical thinking skills necessary to continue onwards as a doctoral student. The exam is broken into two separate parts: a written exam and an oral exam.</description></item><item><title>Keeping Your Desktops in Sync with Dropbox</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/keeping-your-desktop-in-sync-with-dropbox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2012 21:04:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/keeping-your-desktop-in-sync-with-dropbox/</guid><description>Ever since I got my desktop and relegated my laptop to predominately being my work office computer, I have become heavily reliant upon the incredible Dropbox for keeping my files synchronized across the two computers. I had already been keeping my documents backed up to the cloud for several years and amassed about 22GB of free storage space thanks to the invite bonus and a variety of extra space opportunities. I now use the service for keeping my passwords (1Password), my research library (Papers), and even the desktops on both my computers up-to-date.</description></item><item><title>Upgrades and Overclocks</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/upgrades-and-overclocks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 22:06:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/upgrades-and-overclocks/</guid><description>After about two months of using my new Hackintosh without any custom modifications, I decided I wanted to overclock my 3.3GHz Intel Core i5-2500K processor a little bit to see if I would notice a performance increase. However, in order to do this, the horribly inadequate stock Intel CPU cooler needed to be replaced. After a brief search online, I settled on the Cooler Master Hyper 212+ as a suitable replacement for my CPU cooling needs.</description></item><item><title>eSports at SXSW 2012</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/esports-at-sxsw-2012/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 16:12:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/esports-at-sxsw-2012/</guid><description>I went to my first SXSW event this past Saturday (despite the absolute deluge of rain) at the Palmer Event Center for the Screenburn Arcade where the IGN Pro League was putting on a StarCraft 2 showmatch between two community-voted players. Interestingly enough, the players Millenium.Stephano and TteSports.WhiteRa ended up being the winners of the IPL StarLeagues 2 and 3, respectively, which made the match feel even more epic. The Frenchman, Ilyes &amp;ldquo;Stephano&amp;rdquo; Satouri, is arguably the best foreigner (non-Korean) player in the world and definitely one of the best Zerg players globally.</description></item><item><title>Fun with Optics</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/fun-with-optics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 23:34:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/fun-with-optics/</guid><description>I spent my entire Saturday helping out at Explore UT as part of a Biomedical Optics Graduate Organization (BOGO) outreach event. We held three forty-minute-long sessions with about thirty kids (8-11 years old) and taught them about optics and the properties of light. Thanks to some incredible funding from our backing organizations (OSA and SPIE), we were able to provide the kids with numerous hands-on, take-home demos including polarizers, diffraction gratings, UV color-changing beads, and a telescope.</description></item><item><title>Winter in Austin</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/winter-in-austin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 18:09:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/winter-in-austin/</guid><description>This past week has had some absolutely incredible weather, mostly in the upper 70&amp;rsquo;s and mid 80&amp;rsquo;s, but Thursday it decided to dip up into the 90&amp;rsquo;s. After four years of Seattle winters (aka cloudy, cold, and wet), maybe Texas winters aren&amp;rsquo;t all that bad. Sadly it has already dropped back into the mid 60&amp;rsquo;s for the weekend and we might get some thunderstorms early next week. But it&amp;rsquo;s still brilliantly sunny and hopefully indicative of the weather for the next few months.</description></item><item><title>The Hackintosh</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/the-hackintosh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 22:09:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/the-hackintosh/</guid><description>In the weeks leading up to my winter break from classes, I decided I was going to build a gaming computer since I was tired of playing on my laptop. While I was originally planning on just building a beastly Windows machine, I realized it was now ridiculously easy to throw together parts to make a &amp;ldquo;Hackintosh,&amp;rdquo; or a computer running Mac OS X minus the Apple hardware and price. I spent several weeks researching the viability of the Hackintosh build, predominately on TonyMacX86, and selecting the components for my system.</description></item><item><title>Sampling Ice Cream Sandwich</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/sampling-ice-cream-sandwich/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2012 06:22:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/sampling-ice-cream-sandwich/</guid><description>I recently started looking for an Android 4.0 &amp;ldquo;Ice Cream Sandwich&amp;rdquo; ROM for my HTC Inspire (Desire HD) after using CyanogenMod for quite some time. The last nightly CM7 build for Ace was back in November and they&amp;rsquo;re still working hard at getting CM9 up an running. While perusing the XDA Forums for some alternatives to CM7, I ran across an awesome Desire HD build called aospX by Existz. After a quick backup and swap to the recommended radio, I flashed the new ICS-based ROM and was quite pleasantly surprised by the improvements in the latest iteration of the Android operating system (4.</description></item><item><title>Here We Go Again</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/here-we-go-again/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2012 05:59:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/here-we-go-again/</guid><description>Well, it&amp;rsquo;s that time of year again when I randomly and decisively to completely redesign my website. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to abandon the automatically generated Flavors.me profile in favor of a more versatile Wordpress installation (again). I&amp;rsquo;m planning on making the front page a mostly static representation of my real life identity and relying on a few widgets along the bottom to cover some of my more frequently utilized social networks (Twitter and Flickr right now).</description></item><item><title>Research</title><link>https://csullender.com/research/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2012 00:12:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/research/</guid><description>Add me on LinkedIn and ResearchGate. View my CV. Learn about my education.
Advisor: Andrew K. Dunn, Ph.D. (Department of Biomedical Engineering)
Projects
Designed, implemented, and optimized quantitative multimodal optical imaging platform for studying the neurovascular hemodynamics of ischemic stroke. Rapid development of clinical laser speckle contrast imaging (LSCI) system for intraoperative blood flow monitoring during neurosurgery. Modernized multi-exposure speckle imaging (MESI) optical system Development of custom software (Qt C++) for real-time LSCI acquisition, processing, and visualization.</description></item><item><title>Education</title><link>https://csullender.com/education/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2012 00:12:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/education/</guid><description>Add me on LinkedIn and ResearchGate. View my CV. Learn about my research.
Continuing Education Link to heading Coursera: Machine Learning (July 2021) Coursera: AI For Everyone (August 2021) Ph.D., Biomedical Engineering (December 2018)
Dissertation: Quantitative Optical Imaging Platform for Studying Neurovascular Hemodynamics During Ischemic Stroke Certification in Graduate Portfolio Program in Imaging Science and Informatics M.S.E., Biomedical Engineering (May 2016)
Relevant Coursework - Biomedical Imaging Modalities, Biostatistics, Data Mining, Digital Image and Video Processing, Functional Imaging Laboratory, Neurobiology of Disease, Optical Design, Cell and Tissue Engineering, Fundamentals of Biomedical Optical Imaging, Medical Device Design and Manufacturing, Texas Venture Labs Practicum</description></item><item><title>Hello world!</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 00:54:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>Welcome to WordPress. This is your first post. Edit or delete it, then start blogging!</description></item></channel></rss>