<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Software on Colin Sullender</title><link>https://csullender.com/tags/software/</link><description>Recent content in Software on Colin Sullender</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 18:58:02 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csullender.com/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Migrating Hugo deployment to GitHub Actions from TravisCI</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/migrating-to-github-actions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 14:12:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/migrating-to-github-actions/</guid><description>&lt;p>With the &lt;a href="https://mailchi.mp/3d439eeb1098/travis-ciorg-is-moving-to-travis-cicom" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">recent shutdown of travis-ci.org&lt;/a> and the &lt;a href="https://blog.travis-ci.com/2020-11-02-travis-ci-new-billing" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announcement of a new pricing model&lt;/a> for TravisCI with limited free usage, I made the decision to migrate the CI/CD for this website to &lt;a href="https://github.com/features/actions" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub Actions&lt;/a>. As I mentioned &lt;a href="https://csullender.com/posts/goodbye-wordpress-hello-hugo/" >when I first transitioned to using Hugo&lt;/a>, I&amp;rsquo;m still hosting this website on a paid server to retain a few dynamic pages that would not work properly on a &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/hosting-and-deployment/hosting-on-netlify/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Netlify deployment&lt;/a>. The following are the steps that I took to migrate between services.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Goodbye WordPress. Hello Hugo.</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/goodbye-wordpress-hello-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 12:10:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/goodbye-wordpress-hello-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;p>After eight years of &lt;a href="https://csullender.com/posts/hello-world/" >using WordPress&lt;/a>, I finally decided it&amp;rsquo;s time to rid myself of the &lt;a href="https://www.quora.com/Why-is-WordPress-so-bad-and-are-there-any-real-alternatives" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cumbersome, error-prone beast&lt;/a> in favor of a static website. I rarely post blog entries anymore, so the convenience of the WordPress text editor and dynamic content has lost its appeal, especially since this website now primarily serves as a digital portfolio. After far too much research (i.e. perusing Reddit threads), I decided to use a static site generator to create and maintain the new website.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Goodbye BitTorrent Sync. Hello Syncthing.</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/goodbye-bittorrent-sync-hello-syncthing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 19:26:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/goodbye-bittorrent-sync-hello-syncthing/</guid><description>&lt;p>I first started using &lt;a href="https://www.getsync.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BitTorrent Sync&lt;/a> back during its Alpha release in early 2013 as an alternative to Dropbox for syncing large quantities of files across my work computers. I needed an easy way to automatically transfer data from my collection computer to the lab server for storage and to my office computer for post-processing. While I have much more free storage than your average non-paying Dropbox user, I needed to regularly transfer tens of gigabytes of files without any need of uploading to the Internet/cloud. BitTorrent Sync seemed to fulfill that need almost perfectly and was vastly easier than constantly running rsync commands.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automatic Android Location Mode Toggling 2.0</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/automatic-android-location-mode-toggling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 16:14:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/automatic-android-location-mode-toggling/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few months ago I had &lt;a href="https://csullender.com/posts/automatic-high-accuracy-android-location/" title="Automatically Toggle &amp;#39;High Accuracy&amp;#39; Location Mode on Android" >a blog post&lt;/a> about automatically toggling Android Location Mode on my smartphone between &lt;code>High Accuracy&lt;/code> and &lt;code>Battery Saving&lt;/code> when using certain apps. Using the super-app &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=net.dinglisch.android.taskerm" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tasker&lt;/a> and a 3rd-party plugin called &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.intangibleobject.securesettings.plugin" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Secure Settings&lt;/a> I was able to swap the Location Mode of my Nexus 5 between the two modes. However, this was a poor solution since closing an app would result in disabling GPS access, which was undesirable if navigation was currently active. Furthermore, closing an app and returning to it would result in deactivation regardless of the timing. Despite numerous suggestions in the comments, none of them provided a viable answer. Since then, I purchased a &lt;a href="http://amzn.com/B005NLQAHS" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bluetooth OBD&lt;/a> (On-Board Diagnostic) tool to use with the very cool app &lt;a href="https://dash.by/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dash&lt;/a>. This device remains on at all times and the &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dashlabs.dash.android&amp;amp;hl=en" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dash app&lt;/a> is set to automatically connect whenever in range. This automatic connection via Bluetooth is what makes the following modifications to my automatic Location Mode toggling task possible. In practice, any automatically-connecting Bluetooth device in your car (or part of your car) could allow you to use this technique. &lt;strong>As before, you will need root access for Secure Settings to properly function.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automatically Toggle 'High Accuracy' Location Mode on Android</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/automatic-high-accuracy-android-location/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 22:53:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/automatic-high-accuracy-android-location/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://csullender.com/posts/automatic-android-location-mode-toggling/" title="Automatic Android Location Mode Toggling 2.0" >&lt;strong>Check out this blog post for an updated Android Location Mode toggling task&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of Android&amp;rsquo;s most innovative features is &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/landing/now/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Now&lt;/a>, a service that attempts to provide relevant information to the user based on location and time. Unfortunately, in order to utilize the location-based service, your smartphone must provide location information to Google at expense of battery life. When Android 4.4 &amp;ldquo;Kitkat&amp;rdquo; was released in late October, the location settings were updated to include three different modes: High accuracy, battery saving, and device only. The &amp;lsquo;high accuracy&amp;rsquo; mode utilizes GPS, Wi-Fi, and mobile networks to determine location, &amp;lsquo;battery saving&amp;rsquo; only uses Wi-Fi and mobile networks, and &amp;lsquo;device only&amp;rsquo; relies exclusively on GPS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Keeping your Papers Library Synced</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/papers-sync/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:32:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/papers-sync/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a graduate student, one of the most important tools I use practically every single day is a citation and bibliography reference manager. I&amp;rsquo;ve gone through several (&lt;a href="http://endnote.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Endnote&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.mendeley.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mendeley&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.zotero.org/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zotero&lt;/a>, etc.) over the years before finding one I truly liked: &lt;a href="http://www.mekentosj.com/papers/" title="Visit the Papers Website" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Papers&lt;/a>. Initially a Mac-only client, Papers seemed like a native extension of the OS X environment, akin to that of iTunes or iPhoto. With the ability to search online databases, import articles into a &amp;ldquo;library&amp;rdquo; for organization, and cite papers and assemble bibliographies, Papers does everything I needed and wanted from a reference management program. Over the course of its development, numerous features have been added including an iOS app and Windows counterpart.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting MATLAB to work on Mac OS X 10.8 'Mountain Lion'</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/getting-matlab-to-work-in-mountain-lion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 15:36:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/getting-matlab-to-work-in-mountain-lion/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the biggest risks of immediately upgrading to a new operating system is the loss of functionality for vital programs. While developers will scramble to get their apps ready for the sweeping changes oft accompanied by an upgrade to an operating system, it is inevitable that bugs/quirks/errors will surface. As an engineering graduate student, one of the programs I use quite frequently is &lt;a href="http://www.mathworks.com/products/matlab/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MATLAB&lt;/a>, which is built upon the X11 window system for the Apple OS environment. In the latest update to OS X, &lt;a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/HT5293" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple decided to remove X11&lt;/a> in favor of an open-source development called XQuartz. What this means is that if you upgrade to Mountain Lion, MATLAB cannot run because X11 is no longer included in the operating system. While I&amp;rsquo;m sure many will complain about Apple&amp;rsquo;s apparent lack of support for one of the most commonly used technical programs, they did not truly abandon X11. Rather, they have provided development support to the &lt;a href="http://xquartz.macosforge.org/landing/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">XQuartz project&lt;/a> which is effectively an updated version of X11 which was first included in Mac OS X 10.5.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Upgrading to Mountain Lion</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/upgrading-to-mountain-lion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 19:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/upgrading-to-mountain-lion/</guid><description>&lt;p>The release of the latest Apple computer operating system &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/osx/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OS X 10.8 &amp;lsquo;Mountain Lion&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a> has been a &lt;a href="http://www.engadget.com/2012/07/30/apple-reports-three-million-mountain-lion-downloads-in-four-days/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">resounding success&lt;/a> with over 3 million copies sold in less than four days. As with any system update, the Hackintosh community anxiously starts refreshing their favorite websites (&lt;a href="http://www.tonymacx86.com/home.php" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TonyMacx86&lt;/a>) in hopes of reading tales of successful installations before attempting it themselves. After installing the $20 update onto my laptop, I finally decided to give it a whirl on &lt;a href="http://www.csullender.com/blog/2012/02/12/the-hackintosh/" title="The Hackintosh" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">my Hackintosh.&lt;/a> I used the &lt;a href="http://www.tonymacx86.com/61-unibeast-1-5-install-os-x-mountain-lion-any-supported-intel-based-pc.html" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Unibeast&lt;/a> tool from the aforementioned &lt;a href="http://www.tonymacx86.com/home.php" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TonyMacx86&lt;/a> community to create a bootable flash drive with the Mountain Lion installer. A typical installation would then simply require booting off the flash drive, selecting the installation drive, and then enjoying the new OS. Unfortunately, my graphics card (ATI Radeon HD 6870) has had issues with the installation process and requires a few extra steps to get everything working. Without these additional modifications, the installer hangs at the launch screen indefinitely. This fix should work for any ATI Radeon 6XXX card but I have only tried it on the 6870.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Keeping Your Desktops in Sync with Dropbox</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/keeping-your-desktop-in-sync-with-dropbox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2012 21:04:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/keeping-your-desktop-in-sync-with-dropbox/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ever since I got my desktop and relegated my laptop to predominately being my work office computer, I have become heavily reliant upon the incredible &lt;a href="http://db.tt/1M1kZsG" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dropbox&lt;/a> for keeping my files synchronized across the two computers. I had already been keeping my documents backed up to the cloud for several years and amassed about 22GB of free storage space thanks to the invite bonus and a variety of extra space opportunities. I now use the service for keeping my passwords (&lt;a href="https://agilebits.com/onepassword" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1Password&lt;/a>), my research library (&lt;a href="http://www.mekentosj.com/papers/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Papers&lt;/a>), and even the desktops on both my computers up-to-date.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sampling Ice Cream Sandwich</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/sampling-ice-cream-sandwich/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2012 06:22:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/sampling-ice-cream-sandwich/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently started looking for an Android 4.0 &amp;ldquo;Ice Cream Sandwich&amp;rdquo; ROM for my HTC Inspire (Desire HD) after using &lt;a href="http://www.cyanogenmod.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CyanogenMod&lt;/a> for quite some time. The last nightly CM7 build for Ace was back in November and they&amp;rsquo;re still &lt;a href="http://www.cyanogenmod.com/blog/progress-on-cm9" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">working hard at getting CM9 up an running&lt;/a>. While perusing the &lt;a href="http://forum.xda-developers.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">XDA Forums&lt;/a> for some alternatives to CM7, I ran across an &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/aospx/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">awesome Desire HD build called aospX&lt;/a> by Existz. After a quick backup and swap to the recommended radio, I flashed the new ICS-based ROM and was quite pleasantly surprised by the improvements in the latest iteration of the Android operating system (4.0.3 in this case). Aside from feeling considerably more responsive, this ICS build really seems to fix a lot of issues that afflicted the older Gingerbread ROMs I&amp;rsquo;ve used in the past. The built-in data tracking system and seemingly longer battery life are huge factors for me. The ability to launch a camera from the lock screen is incredibly convenient and the new-and-improved Google apps and widgets are orders of magnitude better than their predecessors.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>