<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Design on Colin Sullender</title><link>https://csullender.com/tags/design/</link><description>Recent content in Design on Colin Sullender</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 16:16:18 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csullender.com/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Goodbye WordPress. Hello Hugo.</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/goodbye-wordpress-hello-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 12:10:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/goodbye-wordpress-hello-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;p>After eight years of &lt;a href="https://csullender.com/posts/hello-world/" >using WordPress&lt;/a>, I finally decided it&amp;rsquo;s time to rid myself of the &lt;a href="https://www.quora.com/Why-is-WordPress-so-bad-and-are-there-any-real-alternatives" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cumbersome, error-prone beast&lt;/a> in favor of a static website. I rarely post blog entries anymore, so the convenience of the WordPress text editor and dynamic content has lost its appeal, especially since this website now primarily serves as a digital portfolio. After far too much research (i.e. perusing Reddit threads), I decided to use a static site generator to create and maintain the new website.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Full Page Background Image with CSS3</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/full-page-background-image/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 06:08:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/full-page-background-image/</guid><description>&lt;p>Several of the websites I&amp;rsquo;ve created use a background image as part of the design. It turns out that making the image stay centered, maintain the same aspect ratio, scale with the browser, and always fill the entire page is a difficult task. After several infuriating hours of trial and error, I finally figured out how to make all the above occur in a modern browser using only CSS3. &lt;a href="http://jsfiddle.net/o286bbpg/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Check out this JSFiddle&lt;/a> for an example of it in action or read on for an explanation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Support Dogecoin with Facebook Timeline Cover Images!</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/support-dogecoin-with-facebook-timeline-cover-images/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 22:37:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/support-dogecoin-with-facebook-timeline-cover-images/</guid><description>&lt;p>I made a few &lt;a href="http://dogecoin.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dogecoin&lt;/a>-themed Facebook timeline cover images during &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/dogecoin/comments/1y8bul/fb_cover_photo_all_shibes_should_update_30/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a contest on Reddit&lt;/a> last week. I wanted to create more minimalistic images rather than the extremely busy/stylized images other contestants were presenting. I also wanted to steer away from the Comic Sans MS and &lt;a href="http://knowyourmeme.com/memes/doge" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Doge-speak&lt;/a> in favor of a more serious look. The resulting images are displayed below along with a Facebook demo and anyone is welcome to use them on Facebook (or elsewhere) to show their support for Dogecoin. To the Moon!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Twitter Analytics 2.0</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/twitter-analytics-2-0/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 22:07:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/twitter-analytics-2-0/</guid><description>&lt;p>A couple years ago I made a simple Twitter Stats page to depict my tweeting activity. It was originally powered by some datasets pulled from &lt;a href="http://www.tweetstats.com/" title="Visit Tweetstats" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TweetStats&lt;/a> but I eventually upgraded it to run entirely from my own server. It was extremely barebones and grabbed my &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/shiruken" title="View My Twitter" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Twitter&lt;/a> feed every hour and downloaded all the tweets that had been added since the previous update. Unfortunately, because Twitter does not offer the entire tweeting history via the website or this XML feed, I was missing well over a year of data. Combined with problems accessing this feed, I would regularly lose my entire (local) cache of my Twitter feed and have to spend a lot of time fixing everything. I eventually just decided to kill off the page since I was losing more and more of the older tweets every time I had to fix the cache and Twitter was changing the way the feed was presented.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Website Crafting for BOGO</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/website-crafting-for-bogo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 03:36:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/website-crafting-for-bogo/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the student groups I&amp;rsquo;m involved in at the University of Texas is the &lt;a href="http://studentorgs.engr.utexas.edu/bogo" title="BOGO Website" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Biomedical Optics Graduate Organization&lt;/a> (BOGO). We&amp;rsquo;ve recently had some changes in the leadership and I&amp;rsquo;m now the Treasurer for the group. One of the tasks I decided to undertake was an updated website that keeps better track of our upcoming events as well as helping members announce their publications and achievements. Unfortunately the webspace we&amp;rsquo;re provided by UT is very limited and pretty much can only allow for static webpages (sadly cannot use Wordpress). I spent a few hours throwing together the new design and making it as &lt;em>easy&lt;/em> as possible for future updating of content. Fortunately PHP is available so some of the more frustrating things to update (i.e. the list of members displayed in a table) can be automatically generated from a list of the users. I&amp;rsquo;ve also opted to use Google Calendar and Google Drive to provide functionality on the website in the form of our future events list and contact form. We&amp;rsquo;ve had some trouble in the past with incoming emails getting lost in our mailing list, so hopefully the new contact options will help alleviate that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Darkness over the Dark Knight</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/the-darkness-over-the-dark-knight/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 23:17:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/the-darkness-over-the-dark-knight/</guid><description>&lt;p>As I&amp;rsquo;m sure everyone online already knows, &lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com/2012/07/20/us/colorado-theater-shooting/index.html?hpt=hp_t1" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">tragedy struck Aurora, Colorado&lt;/a> early on Friday morning at a midnight showing of Christopher Nolan&amp;rsquo;s final installment in the Batman franchise. Twelve people lost their lives and over fifty were treated for injuries received during the assault. My thoughts go out to the family members, friends, and residents of Aurora and Denver whose lives were devastated by this senseless violence. I threw together a quick image for use as an avatar or a Facebook Timeline cover that features the Batman symbol. Feel free to share and use them anywhere.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Here We Go Again</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/here-we-go-again/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2012 05:59:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/here-we-go-again/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well, it&amp;rsquo;s that time of year again when I randomly and decisively to completely redesign my website. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to abandon the automatically generated &lt;a href="http://flavors.me/shiruken" title="View My Flavors.me Profile" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Flavors.me profile&lt;/a> in favor of a more versatile Wordpress installation (again). I&amp;rsquo;m planning on making the front page a mostly static representation of my real life identity and relying on a few widgets along the bottom to cover some of my more frequently utilized social networks (Twitter and Flickr right now). Of course, I&amp;rsquo;ll be linking to all the other ones on a separate page or maybe throwing together an aggregate page á la Flavors.me style. Wordpress will also make my planned return to blogging considerably easier (because I really need to ramble online some more). The state of this website will probably be in flux for quite a while since I have to juggle school and work amongst other things to tinker with it, but definitely keep an eye out for some content here in the future. Happy Interneting!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>