<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Esports on Colin Sullender</title><link>https://csullender.com/tags/esports/</link><description>Recent content in Esports on Colin Sullender</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 11:29:44 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csullender.com/tags/esports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Red Bull Battlegrounds</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/red-bull-battlegrounds/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 20:32:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/red-bull-battlegrounds/</guid><description>&lt;p>This past weekend saw the first major competitive video-gaming event take place in Austin, TX as the &lt;a href="http://www.redbullusa.com/cs/Satellite/en_US/Red-Bull-LAN/001243017356310" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Red Bull Battlegrounds&lt;/a> took over the &lt;a href="http://acl-live.com/venue" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Moody Theater&lt;/a> for two days of StarCraft 2 action. A 16-player invitational hosted by Day[9], DJwheat, Husky, and Rob Simpson, the event was a resounding success for a non-major-league (&lt;a href="http://www.majorleaguegaming.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MLG&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="http://www.ign.com/ipl" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">IPL&lt;/a>) live event. I decided to only attend the second day (Sunday) of the tournament since the first day featured a round-robin tournament in which an absolute deluge of games were played. Day 2 took the top 8 players from the previous day and seeded them into a single-elimination bracket to fight for over $40k in prize money.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>eSports at SXSW 2012</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/esports-at-sxsw-2012/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 16:12:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/esports-at-sxsw-2012/</guid><description>&lt;p>I went to my first SXSW event this past Saturday (despite the absolute deluge of rain) at the Palmer Event Center for the &lt;a href="http://sxsw.com/interactive/screenburn" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Screenburn Arcade&lt;/a> where the IGN Pro League was putting on a StarCraft 2 showmatch between two community-voted players. Interestingly enough, the players Millenium.Stephano and TteSports.WhiteRa ended up being the winners of the IPL StarLeagues 2 and 3, respectively, which made the match feel even more epic. The Frenchman, Ilyes &amp;ldquo;Stephano&amp;rdquo; Satouri, is arguably the best foreigner (non-Korean) player in the world and definitely one of the best Zerg players globally. Aleksey &amp;ldquo;White-Ra&amp;rdquo; Krupnyk, hails from the Ukraine, and has been a long-time community favorite for his Protoss &amp;ldquo;special tactics&amp;rdquo; and broken English phrases that are frequently absorbed into the StarCraft eSports lexicon. It was awesome seeing these people play in person after being limited to &lt;a href="http://twitch.tv" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TwitchTV&lt;/a> streams and &lt;a href="http://www.majorleaguegaming.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Major League Gaming&lt;/a> events in the past. Nothing beats a live crowd, especially when an &lt;a href="http://wiki.teamliquid.net/starcraft2/Archon_toilet" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Archon Toilet&lt;/a> results in the nearly instantaneous death of 10+ Brood Lords and a complete change in momentum.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>