<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Music on Colin Sullender</title><link>https://csullender.com/tags/music/</link><description>Recent content in Music on Colin Sullender</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 16:16:18 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csullender.com/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SXSW 2015</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2015/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 02:26:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2015/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another year, another South By, another week of extensive walking and partaking in free parties and concerts. SXSW 2015 has truly turned Austin into a spring break for mid 20-year-olds. As usual, I always go in with zero expectations and just tried to have a good time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first big event was on Saturday at &lt;a href="http://family.do512.com/smartgirlsparty" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amy Poehler&amp;rsquo;s Smart Girls Party&lt;/a> at Banger&amp;rsquo;s Sausage House and Beer Garden which was also where &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/geekandsundry" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Geek &amp;amp; Sundry&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL7atuZxmT956cWFGxqSyRdn6GWhBxiAwE" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tabletop&lt;/a> had all-day events.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Taylor Swifting</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/taylor-swifting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 06:28:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/taylor-swifting/</guid><description>&lt;p>I had a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/shiruken/status/536957959503241217" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">really random idea&lt;/a> the other day for a simple coding project using the LastFM API: When was the last time you listened to Taylor Swift? This is obviously an extremely important statistic to know for the Taylor Swift obsessed. I already made a tool to &lt;a href="https://csullender.com/first" >&lt;del>lookup the first time you listened to an artist&lt;/del>&lt;/a> using your LastFM profile, so this was a relatively straightforward adaptation. I also wanted to take this opportunity to leverage the power of &lt;a href="http://jquery.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">jQuery&lt;/a> to asynchronously load the information rather than simply waiting for a static page. Check out &lt;del>The Last Swifting page&lt;/del> (&lt;em>Deprecated July 2022&lt;/em>) or continue reading for more information.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SXSW 2014</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 00:43:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2014/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another crazy &lt;a href="http://sxsw.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SXSW&lt;/a> has come and gone in Austin, TX, and I&amp;rsquo;m completely exhausted. Unlike the past two years where most of my participation was during the Music portion of the festival, I explored extensively during Interactive (i.e. earlier). The biggest events I attended were the Dropbox party and the multi-day Rachael Ray Feedback House Party. The first was at a brand new bar on Rainey Street called &lt;a href="http://austincontainerbar.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Container Bar&lt;/a> and featured live music from Wild Cub (they&amp;rsquo;re gonna blow up). The second was at an event space on East Cesar Chavez called &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Chick-Ranch-Austin/697801683571177" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chick Ranch&lt;/a> and featured tons of live bands and BBQ from a Chicago restaurant called &lt;a href="http://www.lilliesq.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lillies&lt;/a>. I managed to snag invites to both events for myself and a ton of my friends through some Twitter magic. Besides those, I walked around to a ton of the open venues all across downtown Austin to catch music and eat/drink free stuff. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in seeing my photos, check out &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/shiruken/sets/72157642462282474/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the Flickr set here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Top Music of 2013</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/top-music-of-2013/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 23:35:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/top-music-of-2013/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m really bad at picking my favorite music of the year, so I&amp;rsquo;ll let the &lt;a href="http://www.last.fm/user/shiruken" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LastFM audioscrobbler&lt;/a> do it for me. I figure I listen to whatever I like the most, so it should more or less be representative of my picks for the year. What follows are my &lt;em>favorite&lt;/em> albums and artists of the year based on playcounts!&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="top-10-albums-of-2013">
 Top 10 Albums of 2013
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#top-10-albums-of-2013">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>



&lt;div class="gallery caption-position-center caption-effect-fade hover-effect-grow hover-transition hugo-five" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageGallery">
		

&lt;link rel="stylesheet" href="https://csullender.com/css/hugo-easy-gallery.css" />
&lt;div class="box" >
 &lt;figure itemprop="associatedMedia" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject">
 &lt;div class="img" style="background-image: url('https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/174s/4857b5e7f93d4e1e9bdde4166e7062e6.png');">
 &lt;img itemprop="thumbnail" src="https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/174s/4857b5e7f93d4e1e9bdde4166e7062e6.png" alt="CHVRCHES - The Bones of What You Believe"/>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;a href="https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/174s/4857b5e7f93d4e1e9bdde4166e7062e6.png" itemprop="contentUrl">&lt;/a>
 &lt;figcaption>
 &lt;p>CHVRCHES - The Bones of What You Believe&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>200k LastFM Scrobbles</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/200k-lastfm-scrobbles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 20:25:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/200k-lastfm-scrobbles/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently surpassed the 200,000 song scrobble mark on &lt;a href="http://www.last.fm/user/shiruken" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LastFM&lt;/a> since joining way back in March 2005. I threw together a little infographic summarizing my overall top artists, albums, and songs over the past 8+ years. I&amp;rsquo;m going to make a yearly summary so that all my charts aren&amp;rsquo;t overwhelmed by the stuff I listened to back in high school. Click on the image for the full-sized infographic. Everything was created in Adobe Illustrator using information and images from the LastFM website.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>LastFM First Listen</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/lastfm-first-listen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 03:55:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/lastfm-first-listen/</guid><description>&lt;p>When was the first time you listened to M83? What about LIGHTS? If you&amp;rsquo;re a &lt;a href="http://www.last.fm/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LastFM&lt;/a> user, then I&amp;rsquo;ve made a &lt;del>little web-app&lt;/del> (&lt;em>Deprecated July 2022&lt;/em>) you can use to look it up! All you need is an active LastFM account and to have been tracking your music listening with their scrobbling service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="M83First.jpg" alt="First Time I Listened to M83">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All you need to do is enter any LastFM username and artist and then hit submit. The website uses the LastFM &lt;code>user.getArtistTracks&lt;/code> API method to fetch every single track the user has scrobbled from that particular artist. The XML returned file is segmented into 50 plays-per-page but fortunately reports the total number of pages in the first child element. This number is used to jump to the last page of the data, which contains the very first scrobbled track by the user for the particular artist. From there it&amp;rsquo;s just a matter of parsing the XML structure and grabbing the necessary information for display on the webpage with PHP.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>M83 Live</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/m83-live/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2012 18:39:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/m83-live/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://ilovem83.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">M83&lt;/a> is absolutely one of my favorite bands to see live. While many people find Anthony Gonzalez&amp;rsquo;s heavily shoegaze-influenced music somewhat boring (excluding that one track that everyone knows from &lt;em>Hurry Up, We&amp;rsquo;re Dreaming&lt;/em>), their live performances are anything but that. From the perfectly implemented light show to the random electronic dance jam sessions in the middle of their more upbeat songs, M83 is a blast to see in concert. Even though there were people at the concert who only wanted to hear &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9aZFcosBTaQ" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Midnight City&lt;/a>,&amp;rdquo; there is no denying that the rest of the show was just as energetic. Their extended versions of &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BFD-dR8ToPM" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fall&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; from the &lt;em>TRON: Legacy&lt;/em> soundtrack and &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wrv0F-WTio4" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Couleurs&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; from &lt;em>Saturdays = Youth&lt;/em> were awesome. Even if you&amp;rsquo;re one of the &amp;ldquo;only likes Midnight City&amp;rdquo; crowd, their live performances make that song look boring in comparison. You should seriously see them.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>