<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data Visualization on Colin Sullender</title><link>https://csullender.com/tags/data-visualization/</link><description>Recent content in Data Visualization on Colin Sullender</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 12:44:20 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csullender.com/tags/data-visualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tracking Broken Water Pipes in Austin, TX</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/tracking-broken-water-pipes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/tracking-broken-water-pipes/</guid><description>&lt;p>A massive winter storm in February &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2021/02/19/climate/texas-storm-power-generation-charts.html" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">disrupted power generation across the state of Texas&lt;/a> and caused &lt;a href="https://www.texastribune.org/2021/02/17/texas-winter-storm-power-outage-ercot/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">nearly 3 million households to lose electricity&lt;/a>. As Austin Energy &lt;a href="https://www.statesman.com/story/weather/2021/02/15/austin-energy-begins-rolling-outages-across-city-ease-strain-power-grid/4487244001/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">struggled to implement rolling blackouts&lt;/a> to reduce energy demand, many neighborhoods in the city went multiple days without electricity during &lt;a href="https://www.kxan.com/weather/weather-blog/cold-wave-surpasses-83-arctic-outbreak-enters-record-books/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">record-breaking cold weather&lt;/a>. With residents suddenly unable to heat their homes, Austin and Travis County emergency services &lt;a href="https://www.statesman.com/story/news/2021/02/15/winter-storm-texas-hundreds-austin-report-broken-water-pipes-request-medical-services/6760606002/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">were flooded with calls about broken water pipes&lt;/a>. By late afternoon on February 15th, the Austin Fire Department&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://www.austintexas.gov/fact/default.cfm" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Active Fire Incidents&lt;/a> page was filled with dozens of &amp;ldquo;BWP - Broken Water Pipe&amp;rdquo; incident reports.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Three Years of 'Science GIFs' on Google+</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/three-years-of-science-gifs-on-google/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 03:13:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/three-years-of-science-gifs-on-google/</guid><description>&lt;p>Three years ago, Google &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/&amp;#43;googleplus/posts/7ZpGWeou2sV" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced&lt;/a> the Collections feature on the Google+ social network. It offered a way to group posts by topic so that others could follow their specific interests rather than &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/&amp;#43;ColinSullender" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">your entire profile&lt;/a>. I created two collections, &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/collection/MX98P" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Data is Beautiful&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/collection/A2NSc" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Science GIFs&lt;/a>, the latter of which I&amp;rsquo;ve maintained for almost three years now. Every week I post a science-related GIF and an accompanying explanation of the finding, physical phenomenon, or chemical reaction. I try to feature recent research publications and announcements whenever possible to avoid reposting content seen elsewhere online.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reddit and the Death of Stephen Hawking</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/reddit-and-the-death-of-stephen-hawking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 04:46:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/reddit-and-the-death-of-stephen-hawking/</guid><description>&lt;p>As the news of &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-43396008" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Stephen Hawking&amp;rsquo;s death&lt;/a> reverberated across the internet, the &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/science/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">r/science community&lt;/a> on Reddit made an unusual post: &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/84aiy6/physicist_stephen_hawking_dies_aged_76/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">An opportunity to discuss the life of one of humanity&amp;rsquo;s greatest minds&lt;/a>. It was the first post of its kind in a subreddit normally dedicated to talking about science papers. However, the moderator team decided his passing warranted acknowledgement given his contributions to physics and his role as the most widely recognized science communicator on the planet. He had also previously participated in &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/3nyn5i/science_ama_series_stephen_hawking_ama_answers/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an Ask Me Anything&lt;/a> in our subreddit.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SXSW 2015</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2015/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 02:26:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2015/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another year, another South By, another week of extensive walking and partaking in free parties and concerts. SXSW 2015 has truly turned Austin into a spring break for mid 20-year-olds. As usual, I always go in with zero expectations and just tried to have a good time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first big event was on Saturday at &lt;a href="http://family.do512.com/smartgirlsparty" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amy Poehler&amp;rsquo;s Smart Girls Party&lt;/a> at Banger&amp;rsquo;s Sausage House and Beer Garden which was also where &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/geekandsundry" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Geek &amp;amp; Sundry&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL7atuZxmT956cWFGxqSyRdn6GWhBxiAwE" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tabletop&lt;/a> had all-day events.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hackintosh 2.0 Benchmark</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/hackintosh-2.0-benchmark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 21:37:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/hackintosh-2.0-benchmark/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since I am obsessed with quantifying things, I absolutely had to benchmark my &lt;a href="https://csullender.com/posts/hackintosh-2.0/" title="Hackintosh 2.0" >new Hackintosh rig&lt;/a> to see what my new purchases had afforded cost me. I ran a handful of different benchmarks under both OS X and Windows boots to see what the &lt;a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16819117372" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Intel Core i5-4690K&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16814487076" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EVGA GeForce GTX 970 SC&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16820147360" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Samsung 850 Pro&lt;/a> could do. So without further ado, here are the results of my benchmarks!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="Header.jpg" alt="Header">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="geekbenchhttpswwwgeekbenchcom">
 &lt;a href="https://www.geekbench.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Geekbench&lt;/a>
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#geekbenchhttpswwwgeekbenchcom">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Tested processor performance across &lt;a href="https://csullender.com/posts/the-hackintosh/" title="The Hackintosh" >Hackintosh v1.0&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://csullender.com/posts/hackintosh-2.0/" title="Hackintosh 2.0" >v2.0&lt;/a>, and a MacBook Pro (Early 2011, 15-inch). All tests were conducted 5 times and averaged together on OS X 10.10.1 Yosemite with no overclocking. While the i5-2500K (3.3GHz) in my original Hackintosh had similar performance to the i7-2720QM (2.2GHz) in the MacBook Pro, the i5-4690K (3.5GHz) offers all-around better performance. &lt;strong>Based on overall Geekbench scores, the Hackintosh v2.0 system is roughly 33% better than its predecessor.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Scholar Visualization</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/google-scholar-visualization/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 16:59:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/google-scholar-visualization/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the most common images I see during science presentations is the frequency of publications within a particular field over time. It&amp;rsquo;s a great way to show the growth of the field while attempting to validate the worthiness of the research that follows. As far as I can tell, most people manually assemble this data with sequential searches on &lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Scholar&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://webofknowledge.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Web of Science&lt;/a>. This seemed like a straightforward opportunity for automation, so &lt;del>I made a little website&lt;/del> (&lt;em>Deprecated July 2022&lt;/em>) that does just that. It takes a Google Scholar search query and a range of years and plots the number of results over time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Half a Year with Dash</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/half-a-year-with-dash/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2014 20:48:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/half-a-year-with-dash/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using &lt;a href="https://dash.by/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dash&lt;/a> in my car for almost six months now to track my driving habits and monitor my car&amp;rsquo;s status. The app interfaces over Bluetooth with an OBD device to read engine codes and access metrics such as speed, fuel efficiency, and engine status. The app tracks every trip and assigns a &amp;ldquo;Driving Score&amp;rdquo; based on driving behavior to encourage &amp;ldquo;better&amp;rdquo; driving habits. Currently the only way to access the data is &lt;a href="https://ifttt.com/dash" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">via an IFTTT channel&lt;/a> that logs each trip to a line of a Google Spreadsheet. The developer is working on an &lt;a href="https://dash.by/developers" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">API (aptly named Chassis)&lt;/a> that will hopefully make access to the data even easier in the coming future. In the meantime, I just used the IFTTT spreadsheet output to assemble some stats and charts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SXSW 2014</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 00:43:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2014/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another crazy &lt;a href="http://sxsw.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SXSW&lt;/a> has come and gone in Austin, TX, and I&amp;rsquo;m completely exhausted. Unlike the past two years where most of my participation was during the Music portion of the festival, I explored extensively during Interactive (i.e. earlier). The biggest events I attended were the Dropbox party and the multi-day Rachael Ray Feedback House Party. The first was at a brand new bar on Rainey Street called &lt;a href="http://austincontainerbar.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Container Bar&lt;/a> and featured live music from Wild Cub (they&amp;rsquo;re gonna blow up). The second was at an event space on East Cesar Chavez called &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Chick-Ranch-Austin/697801683571177" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chick Ranch&lt;/a> and featured tons of live bands and BBQ from a Chicago restaurant called &lt;a href="http://www.lilliesq.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lillies&lt;/a>. I managed to snag invites to both events for myself and a ton of my friends through some Twitter magic. Besides those, I walked around to a ton of the open venues all across downtown Austin to catch music and eat/drink free stuff. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in seeing my photos, check out &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/shiruken/sets/72157642462282474/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the Flickr set here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>200k LastFM Scrobbles</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/200k-lastfm-scrobbles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 20:25:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/200k-lastfm-scrobbles/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently surpassed the 200,000 song scrobble mark on &lt;a href="http://www.last.fm/user/shiruken" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LastFM&lt;/a> since joining way back in March 2005. I threw together a little infographic summarizing my overall top artists, albums, and songs over the past 8+ years. I&amp;rsquo;m going to make a yearly summary so that all my charts aren&amp;rsquo;t overwhelmed by the stuff I listened to back in high school. Click on the image for the full-sized infographic. Everything was created in Adobe Illustrator using information and images from the LastFM website.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3 Months of Fitbit</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/3-months-of-fitbit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 23:31:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/3-months-of-fitbit/</guid><description>&lt;p>I bought myself a &lt;a href="http://www.fitbit.com/one" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fitbit One&lt;/a> right before the New Year in hopes of motivating more physical activity to offset my stationary lab lifestyle. It&amp;rsquo;s been just over three months since I started tracking my daily steps and most of my sleep. While I haven&amp;rsquo;t started running yet (I promise I&amp;rsquo;ll start eventually), it&amp;rsquo;s been fascinating to see my walking activity tracked throughout the day. One of my biggest complaints about Fitbit&amp;rsquo;s services is that they make you pay to access in-depth information about your activity. I think that it&amp;rsquo;s absolutely ludicrous to charge $49.99 a year to see the full extent of your data. With that said, they do offer an API for third-party development with access to the raw data (steps, distance, etc.) so I used this to &lt;a href="http://quantifiedself.com/2013/02/how-to-download-fitbit-data-using-google-spreadsheets/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">automatically pull&lt;/a> my daily activity into a Google Drive spreadsheet for easy access and analysis. Using this data, I generate my &lt;a href="http://www.csullender.com/health/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&amp;ldquo;health tracking&amp;rdquo; page&lt;/a> featuring several charts of my ongoing Fitbit activity. The remainder of this post presents a summary of my Fitbit activity over the past 90 days since I got the One.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Upgrades and Overclocks</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/upgrades-and-overclocks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 22:06:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/upgrades-and-overclocks/</guid><description>&lt;p>After about two months of using my new &lt;a href="http://www.csullender.com/blog/2012/02/12/the-hackintosh/" title="The Hackintosh" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hackintosh&lt;/a> without any custom modifications, I decided I wanted to overclock my 3.3GHz &lt;a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16819115072" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Intel Core i5-2500K&lt;/a> processor a little bit to see if I would notice a performance increase. However, in order to do this, the horribly inadequate stock Intel CPU cooler needed to be replaced. After a brief search online, I settled on the &lt;a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16835103065" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cooler Master Hyper 212+&lt;/a> as a suitable replacement for my CPU cooling needs. After an excruciating two-day wait, the part finally came in and I began the installation process of this gargantuan new cooling unit that just barely fit into my case. The new heatsink offered easily 10x more surface area for heat dissipation, which drastically increased the cooling efficiency of the running CPU. With the stock cooler, I saw the CPU idling around 45-50C. In stark contrast, the overclocked system now idles around 35C.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>