<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tips &amp; Tricks on Colin Sullender</title><link>https://csullender.com/tags/tips-tricks/</link><description>Recent content in Tips &amp; Tricks on Colin Sullender</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 14:12:14 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csullender.com/tags/tips-tricks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Migrating Hugo deployment to GitHub Actions from TravisCI</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/migrating-to-github-actions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 14:12:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/migrating-to-github-actions/</guid><description>With the recent shutdown of travis-ci.org and the announcement of a new pricing model for TravisCI with limited free usage, I made the decision to migrate the CI/CD for this website to GitHub Actions. As I mentioned when I first transitioned to using Hugo, I&amp;rsquo;m still hosting this website on a paid server to retain a few dynamic pages that would not work properly on a Netlify deployment. The following are the steps that I took to migrate between services.</description></item><item><title>Goodbye WordPress. Hello Hugo.</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/goodbye-wordpress-hello-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 12:10:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/goodbye-wordpress-hello-hugo/</guid><description>After eight years of using WordPress, I finally decided it&amp;rsquo;s time to rid myself of the cumbersome, error-prone beast in favor of a static website. I rarely post blog entries anymore, so the convenience of the WordPress text editor and dynamic content has lost its appeal, especially since this website now primarily serves as a digital portfolio. After far too much research (i.e. perusing Reddit threads), I decided to use a static site generator to create and maintain the new website.</description></item><item><title>Goodbye BitTorrent Sync. Hello Syncthing.</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/goodbye-bittorrent-sync-hello-syncthing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 19:26:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/goodbye-bittorrent-sync-hello-syncthing/</guid><description>I first started using BitTorrent Sync back during its Alpha release in early 2013 as an alternative to Dropbox for syncing large quantities of files across my work computers. I needed an easy way to automatically transfer data from my collection computer to the lab server for storage and to my office computer for post-processing. While I have much more free storage than your average non-paying Dropbox user, I needed to regularly transfer tens of gigabytes of files without any need of uploading to the Internet/cloud.</description></item><item><title>Hackintosh 2.0</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/hackintosh-2.0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 04:58:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/hackintosh-2.0/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been roughly two years since I built my original Hackintosh desktop computer and I decided earlier this year that the time was ripe for an upgrade. After considerable waffling on the exact components to get, I finally settled on an relatively high-end build largely based on the December CustoMac Buyer&amp;rsquo;s Guide that reused a few components from my original Hackintosh (case, power supply, and memory).
Gigabyte GA-Z97X-UD5H (Motherboard) Intel Core i5-4690K (CPU) EVGA GeForce GTX 970 Superclocked (GPU) Samsung 850 Pro SSD 256GB (SSD) TP-Link PCI Express Wifi Adapter (WiFi) The most difficult decision by far concerned the graphics card since the current generation Mac Pro uses a custom AMD GPU whereas most Hackintosh guides recommend NVIDIA cards.</description></item><item><title>Full Page Background Image with CSS3</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/full-page-background-image/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 06:08:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/full-page-background-image/</guid><description>Several of the websites I&amp;rsquo;ve created use a background image as part of the design. It turns out that making the image stay centered, maintain the same aspect ratio, scale with the browser, and always fill the entire page is a difficult task. After several infuriating hours of trial and error, I finally figured out how to make all the above occur in a modern browser using only CSS3. Check out this JSFiddle for an example of it in action or read on for an explanation.</description></item><item><title>Automatic Android Location Mode Toggling 2.0</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/automatic-android-location-mode-toggling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 16:14:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/automatic-android-location-mode-toggling/</guid><description>A few months ago I had a blog post about automatically toggling Android Location Mode on my smartphone between High Accuracy and Battery Saving when using certain apps. Using the super-app Tasker and a 3rd-party plugin called Secure Settings I was able to swap the Location Mode of my Nexus 5 between the two modes. However, this was a poor solution since closing an app would result in disabling GPS access, which was undesirable if navigation was currently active.</description></item><item><title>Automatically Toggle 'High Accuracy' Location Mode on Android</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/automatic-high-accuracy-android-location/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 22:53:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/automatic-high-accuracy-android-location/</guid><description>Check out this blog post for an updated Android Location Mode toggling task
One of Android&amp;rsquo;s most innovative features is Google Now, a service that attempts to provide relevant information to the user based on location and time. Unfortunately, in order to utilize the location-based service, your smartphone must provide location information to Google at expense of battery life. When Android 4.4 &amp;ldquo;Kitkat&amp;rdquo; was released in late October, the location settings were updated to include three different modes: High accuracy, battery saving, and device only.</description></item><item><title>Quickstart Dogecoin blockchain sync with bootstrap.dat</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/quickstart-dogecoin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 01:00:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/quickstart-dogecoin/</guid><description>While Bitcoin is the undisputed leader of the cryptocurrency world, a meme-based alternative called Dogecoin has gained steam over the past month. Sporting the comical Shiba Inu dog character from the &amp;ldquo;doge&amp;rdquo; meme, this altcoin gained significant media coverage recently after helping raise $30,000 for the Jamaican bobsled team for the 2014 Sochi Winter Olympics. Promoters of this cryptocurrency have been extremely vocal about the carefree attitude surrounding Dogecoin and actively encourage giving freely to others (tipping) in order to raise awareness.</description></item><item><title>Get the Price of Bitcoin with Google Now</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/google-now-bitcoin-price/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 00:31:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/google-now-bitcoin-price/</guid><description>The digital currency Bitcoin has grown increasingly popular in recent months as more and more businesses have begun accepting the peer-to-peer cryptocurrency. Keeping up with the highly volatile price of Bitcion (BTC) is a must for traders, who use exchanges such as Mt.Gox or BTC-E to turn a profit. Even the casual holder through services such as Coinbase need to see how much their BTC are worth. While there are many websites that track the price of BTC across exchanges, there is no official integration into Google&amp;rsquo;s search engine.</description></item><item><title>Fixing a Broken Google Wallet</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/fixing-a-broken-google-wallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 03:06:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/fixing-a-broken-google-wallet/</guid><description>I recently upgraded to a Google Nexus 4 phone from my old HTC Inspire HD. Unfortunately, the original device that I received had some problems with the ear-piece, resulting in a very noticeable static hissing noise during calls and even when the phone wasn&amp;rsquo;t in use. I decided to RMA the defective device to Google in exchange for a replacement. After several weeks of waiting, I finally got my hands on my Rev.</description></item><item><title>Keeping your Papers Library Synced</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/papers-sync/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:32:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/papers-sync/</guid><description>As a graduate student, one of the most important tools I use practically every single day is a citation and bibliography reference manager. I&amp;rsquo;ve gone through several (Endnote, Mendeley, Zotero, etc.) over the years before finding one I truly liked: Papers. Initially a Mac-only client, Papers seemed like a native extension of the OS X environment, akin to that of iTunes or iPhoto. With the ability to search online databases, import articles into a &amp;ldquo;library&amp;rdquo; for organization, and cite papers and assemble bibliographies, Papers does everything I needed and wanted from a reference management program.</description></item><item><title>Prevent Bootcamp Partition from Mounting</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/prevent-bootcamp-partition-from-automatically-mounting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 04:34:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/prevent-bootcamp-partition-from-automatically-mounting/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re on a Mac with Windows installed via Bootcamp then you&amp;rsquo;ve no doubt noticed that the Bootcamp partition mounts as another drive when using OSX. I rarely needed access to the contents of my Bootcamp installation so I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be nice to prevent the partition from mounting at all on the Mac side of things. There&amp;rsquo;s a relatively easy way to achieve this using just a little bit of command line fiddling.</description></item><item><title>Getting MATLAB to work on Mac OS X 10.8 'Mountain Lion'</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/getting-matlab-to-work-in-mountain-lion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 15:36:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/getting-matlab-to-work-in-mountain-lion/</guid><description>One of the biggest risks of immediately upgrading to a new operating system is the loss of functionality for vital programs. While developers will scramble to get their apps ready for the sweeping changes oft accompanied by an upgrade to an operating system, it is inevitable that bugs/quirks/errors will surface. As an engineering graduate student, one of the programs I use quite frequently is MATLAB, which is built upon the X11 window system for the Apple OS environment.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading to Mountain Lion</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/upgrading-to-mountain-lion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 19:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/upgrading-to-mountain-lion/</guid><description>The release of the latest Apple computer operating system OS X 10.8 &amp;lsquo;Mountain Lion&amp;rsquo; has been a resounding success with over 3 million copies sold in less than four days. As with any system update, the Hackintosh community anxiously starts refreshing their favorite websites (TonyMacx86) in hopes of reading tales of successful installations before attempting it themselves. After installing the $20 update onto my laptop, I finally decided to give it a whirl on my Hackintosh.</description></item><item><title>Keeping Your Desktops in Sync with Dropbox</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/keeping-your-desktop-in-sync-with-dropbox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2012 21:04:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/keeping-your-desktop-in-sync-with-dropbox/</guid><description>Ever since I got my desktop and relegated my laptop to predominately being my work office computer, I have become heavily reliant upon the incredible Dropbox for keeping my files synchronized across the two computers. I had already been keeping my documents backed up to the cloud for several years and amassed about 22GB of free storage space thanks to the invite bonus and a variety of extra space opportunities. I now use the service for keeping my passwords (1Password), my research library (Papers), and even the desktops on both my computers up-to-date.</description></item></channel></rss>