<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Android on Colin Sullender</title><link>https://csullender.com/tags/android/</link><description>Recent content in Android on Colin Sullender</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 15:59:47 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csullender.com/tags/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automatic Android Location Mode Toggling 2.0</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/automatic-android-location-mode-toggling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 16:14:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/automatic-android-location-mode-toggling/</guid><description>A few months ago I had a blog post about automatically toggling Android Location Mode on my smartphone between High Accuracy and Battery Saving when using certain apps. Using the super-app Tasker and a 3rd-party plugin called Secure Settings I was able to swap the Location Mode of my Nexus 5 between the two modes. However, this was a poor solution since closing an app would result in disabling GPS access, which was undesirable if navigation was currently active.</description></item><item><title>Automatically Toggle 'High Accuracy' Location Mode on Android</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/automatic-high-accuracy-android-location/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 22:53:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/automatic-high-accuracy-android-location/</guid><description>Check out this blog post for an updated Android Location Mode toggling task
One of Android&amp;rsquo;s most innovative features is Google Now, a service that attempts to provide relevant information to the user based on location and time. Unfortunately, in order to utilize the location-based service, your smartphone must provide location information to Google at expense of battery life. When Android 4.4 &amp;ldquo;Kitkat&amp;rdquo; was released in late October, the location settings were updated to include three different modes: High accuracy, battery saving, and device only.</description></item><item><title>Get the Price of Bitcoin with Google Now</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/google-now-bitcoin-price/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 00:31:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/google-now-bitcoin-price/</guid><description>The digital currency Bitcoin has grown increasingly popular in recent months as more and more businesses have begun accepting the peer-to-peer cryptocurrency. Keeping up with the highly volatile price of Bitcion (BTC) is a must for traders, who use exchanges such as Mt.Gox or BTC-E to turn a profit. Even the casual holder through services such as Coinbase need to see how much their BTC are worth. While there are many websites that track the price of BTC across exchanges, there is no official integration into Google&amp;rsquo;s search engine.</description></item><item><title>Fixing a Broken Google Wallet</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/fixing-a-broken-google-wallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 03:06:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/fixing-a-broken-google-wallet/</guid><description>I recently upgraded to a Google Nexus 4 phone from my old HTC Inspire HD. Unfortunately, the original device that I received had some problems with the ear-piece, resulting in a very noticeable static hissing noise during calls and even when the phone wasn&amp;rsquo;t in use. I decided to RMA the defective device to Google in exchange for a replacement. After several weeks of waiting, I finally got my hands on my Rev.</description></item><item><title>Sampling Ice Cream Sandwich</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/sampling-ice-cream-sandwich/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2012 06:22:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/sampling-ice-cream-sandwich/</guid><description>I recently started looking for an Android 4.0 &amp;ldquo;Ice Cream Sandwich&amp;rdquo; ROM for my HTC Inspire (Desire HD) after using CyanogenMod for quite some time. The last nightly CM7 build for Ace was back in November and they&amp;rsquo;re still working hard at getting CM9 up an running. While perusing the XDA Forums for some alternatives to CM7, I ran across an awesome Desire HD build called aospX by Existz. After a quick backup and swap to the recommended radio, I flashed the new ICS-based ROM and was quite pleasantly surprised by the improvements in the latest iteration of the Android operating system (4.</description></item></channel></rss>