<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>LastFM on Colin Sullender</title><link>https://csullender.com/tags/lastfm/</link><description>Recent content in LastFM on Colin Sullender</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 16:16:18 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csullender.com/tags/lastfm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Taylor Swifting</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/taylor-swifting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 06:28:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/taylor-swifting/</guid><description>I had a really random idea the other day for a simple coding project using the LastFM API: When was the last time you listened to Taylor Swift? This is obviously an extremely important statistic to know for the Taylor Swift obsessed. I already made a tool to lookup the first time you listened to an artist using your LastFM profile, so this was a relatively straightforward adaptation. I also wanted to take this opportunity to leverage the power of jQuery to asynchronously load the information rather than simply waiting for a static page.</description></item><item><title>Top Music of 2013</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/top-music-of-2013/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 23:35:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/top-music-of-2013/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m really bad at picking my favorite music of the year, so I&amp;rsquo;ll let the LastFM audioscrobbler do it for me. I figure I listen to whatever I like the most, so it should more or less be representative of my picks for the year. What follows are my favorite albums and artists of the year based on playcounts!
Top 10 Albums of 2013 Link to heading CHVRCHES - The Bones of What You Believe</description></item><item><title>LastFM First Listen</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/lastfm-first-listen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 03:55:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/lastfm-first-listen/</guid><description>When was the first time you listened to M83? What about LIGHTS? If you&amp;rsquo;re a LastFM user, then I&amp;rsquo;ve made a little web-app (Deprecated July 2022) you can use to look it up! All you need is an active LastFM account and to have been tracking your music listening with their scrobbling service.
All you need to do is enter any LastFM username and artist and then hit submit. The website uses the LastFM user.</description></item></channel></rss>