<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Austin on Colin Sullender</title><link>https://csullender.com/tags/austin/</link><description>Recent content in Austin on Colin Sullender</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 15:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csullender.com/tags/austin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tracking Broken Water Pipes in Austin, TX</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/tracking-broken-water-pipes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/tracking-broken-water-pipes/</guid><description>A massive winter storm in February disrupted power generation across the state of Texas and caused nearly 3 million households to lose electricity. As Austin Energy struggled to implement rolling blackouts to reduce energy demand, many neighborhoods in the city went multiple days without electricity during record-breaking cold weather. With residents suddenly unable to heat their homes, Austin and Travis County emergency services were flooded with calls about broken water pipes.</description></item><item><title>SXSW 2015</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2015/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 02:26:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2015/</guid><description>Another year, another South By, another week of extensive walking and partaking in free parties and concerts. SXSW 2015 has truly turned Austin into a spring break for mid 20-year-olds. As usual, I always go in with zero expectations and just tried to have a good time.
The first big event was on Saturday at Amy Poehler&amp;rsquo;s Smart Girls Party at Banger&amp;rsquo;s Sausage House and Beer Garden which was also where Geek &amp;amp; Sundry and Tabletop had all-day events.</description></item><item><title>MotoGP ATX 2014</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/motogp-atx-2014/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 01:28:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/motogp-atx-2014/</guid><description>The Red Bull Grand Prix of the Americas was this past weekend at the Circuit of the Americas in Austin, TX. The event spans three days with practice and qualifiers occurring on Saturday and the races for the three classes (MotoGP, Moto2, and Moto3) occurring on Sunday. I attended both days of weekend events and had a great time watching beastly motorcycles roar past Turn 1. I&amp;rsquo;ve included a selection of photos and videos below.</description></item><item><title>SXSW 2014</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 00:43:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2014/</guid><description>Another crazy SXSW has come and gone in Austin, TX, and I&amp;rsquo;m completely exhausted. Unlike the past two years where most of my participation was during the Music portion of the festival, I explored extensively during Interactive (i.e. earlier). The biggest events I attended were the Dropbox party and the multi-day Rachael Ray Feedback House Party. The first was at a brand new bar on Rainey Street called Container Bar and featured live music from Wild Cub (they&amp;rsquo;re gonna blow up).</description></item><item><title>Foursquare Heatmap</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/foursquare-heatmap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 23:06:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/foursquare-heatmap/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a regular user of the location-based social network Foursquare mainly as a source of recommendations for new places to try. I typically check in everywhere I go with the exception of private residences (can&amp;rsquo;t let people stalk me that easily), so I have a pretty extensive log covering my location history. While it&amp;rsquo;s not quite as extensive as the Google Maps Location History, it does a good job representing the places I visit.</description></item><item><title>Red Bull Battlegrounds</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/red-bull-battlegrounds/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 20:32:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/red-bull-battlegrounds/</guid><description>This past weekend saw the first major competitive video-gaming event take place in Austin, TX as the Red Bull Battlegrounds took over the Moody Theater for two days of StarCraft 2 action. A 16-player invitational hosted by Day[9], DJwheat, Husky, and Rob Simpson, the event was a resounding success for a non-major-league (MLG or IPL) live event. I decided to only attend the second day (Sunday) of the tournament since the first day featured a round-robin tournament in which an absolute deluge of games were played.</description></item><item><title>eSports at SXSW 2012</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/esports-at-sxsw-2012/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 16:12:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/esports-at-sxsw-2012/</guid><description>I went to my first SXSW event this past Saturday (despite the absolute deluge of rain) at the Palmer Event Center for the Screenburn Arcade where the IGN Pro League was putting on a StarCraft 2 showmatch between two community-voted players. Interestingly enough, the players Millenium.Stephano and TteSports.WhiteRa ended up being the winners of the IPL StarLeagues 2 and 3, respectively, which made the match feel even more epic. The Frenchman, Ilyes &amp;ldquo;Stephano&amp;rdquo; Satouri, is arguably the best foreigner (non-Korean) player in the world and definitely one of the best Zerg players globally.</description></item><item><title>Winter in Austin</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/winter-in-austin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 18:09:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/winter-in-austin/</guid><description>This past week has had some absolutely incredible weather, mostly in the upper 70&amp;rsquo;s and mid 80&amp;rsquo;s, but Thursday it decided to dip up into the 90&amp;rsquo;s. After four years of Seattle winters (aka cloudy, cold, and wet), maybe Texas winters aren&amp;rsquo;t all that bad. Sadly it has already dropped back into the mid 60&amp;rsquo;s for the weekend and we might get some thunderstorms early next week. But it&amp;rsquo;s still brilliantly sunny and hopefully indicative of the weather for the next few months.</description></item></channel></rss>