<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apple on Colin Sullender</title><link>https://csullender.com/tags/apple/</link><description>Recent content in Apple on Colin Sullender</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 21:37:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csullender.com/tags/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hackintosh 2.0 Benchmark</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/hackintosh-2.0-benchmark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 21:37:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/hackintosh-2.0-benchmark/</guid><description>Since I am obsessed with quantifying things, I absolutely had to benchmark my new Hackintosh rig to see what my new purchases had afforded cost me. I ran a handful of different benchmarks under both OS X and Windows boots to see what the Intel Core i5-4690K, EVGA GeForce GTX 970 SC, and Samsung 850 Pro could do. So without further ado, here are the results of my benchmarks!
Geekbench Link to heading Tested processor performance across Hackintosh v1.</description></item><item><title>Hackintosh 2.0</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/hackintosh-2.0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 04:58:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/hackintosh-2.0/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been roughly two years since I built my original Hackintosh desktop computer and I decided earlier this year that the time was ripe for an upgrade. After considerable waffling on the exact components to get, I finally settled on an relatively high-end build largely based on the December CustoMac Buyer&amp;rsquo;s Guide that reused a few components from my original Hackintosh (case, power supply, and memory).
Gigabyte GA-Z97X-UD5H (Motherboard) Intel Core i5-4690K (CPU) EVGA GeForce GTX 970 Superclocked (GPU) Samsung 850 Pro SSD 256GB (SSD) TP-Link PCI Express Wifi Adapter (WiFi) The most difficult decision by far concerned the graphics card since the current generation Mac Pro uses a custom AMD GPU whereas most Hackintosh guides recommend NVIDIA cards.</description></item><item><title>Prevent Bootcamp Partition from Mounting</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/prevent-bootcamp-partition-from-automatically-mounting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 04:34:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/prevent-bootcamp-partition-from-automatically-mounting/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re on a Mac with Windows installed via Bootcamp then you&amp;rsquo;ve no doubt noticed that the Bootcamp partition mounts as another drive when using OSX. I rarely needed access to the contents of my Bootcamp installation so I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be nice to prevent the partition from mounting at all on the Mac side of things. There&amp;rsquo;s a relatively easy way to achieve this using just a little bit of command line fiddling.</description></item><item><title>Sad Mac: The Chronology of a Broken MacBook Pro</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/sad-mac/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 18:08:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/sad-mac/</guid><description>The following is a record of the problems I encountered with my MacBook Pro (Early 2011) beginning in late August and hopefully culminating in a once-again functional laptop. I&amp;rsquo;m making an effort to document all of the steps I took in attempting to rectify the situation including my experience with the Apple Retail Store. I&amp;rsquo;ve had great experiences with the repair team at Apple Stores in the past and I hope this will continue the trend.</description></item><item><title>Getting MATLAB to work on Mac OS X 10.8 'Mountain Lion'</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/getting-matlab-to-work-in-mountain-lion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 15:36:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/getting-matlab-to-work-in-mountain-lion/</guid><description>One of the biggest risks of immediately upgrading to a new operating system is the loss of functionality for vital programs. While developers will scramble to get their apps ready for the sweeping changes oft accompanied by an upgrade to an operating system, it is inevitable that bugs/quirks/errors will surface. As an engineering graduate student, one of the programs I use quite frequently is MATLAB, which is built upon the X11 window system for the Apple OS environment.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading to Mountain Lion</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/upgrading-to-mountain-lion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 19:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/upgrading-to-mountain-lion/</guid><description>The release of the latest Apple computer operating system OS X 10.8 &amp;lsquo;Mountain Lion&amp;rsquo; has been a resounding success with over 3 million copies sold in less than four days. As with any system update, the Hackintosh community anxiously starts refreshing their favorite websites (TonyMacx86) in hopes of reading tales of successful installations before attempting it themselves. After installing the $20 update onto my laptop, I finally decided to give it a whirl on my Hackintosh.</description></item><item><title>Upgrades and Overclocks</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/upgrades-and-overclocks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 22:06:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/upgrades-and-overclocks/</guid><description>After about two months of using my new Hackintosh without any custom modifications, I decided I wanted to overclock my 3.3GHz Intel Core i5-2500K processor a little bit to see if I would notice a performance increase. However, in order to do this, the horribly inadequate stock Intel CPU cooler needed to be replaced. After a brief search online, I settled on the Cooler Master Hyper 212+ as a suitable replacement for my CPU cooling needs.</description></item><item><title>The Hackintosh</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/the-hackintosh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 22:09:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/the-hackintosh/</guid><description>In the weeks leading up to my winter break from classes, I decided I was going to build a gaming computer since I was tired of playing on my laptop. While I was originally planning on just building a beastly Windows machine, I realized it was now ridiculously easy to throw together parts to make a &amp;ldquo;Hackintosh,&amp;rdquo; or a computer running Mac OS X minus the Apple hardware and price. I spent several weeks researching the viability of the Hackintosh build, predominately on TonyMacX86, and selecting the components for my system.</description></item></channel></rss>