<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apple on Colin Sullender</title><link>https://csullender.com/tags/apple/</link><description>Recent content in Apple on Colin Sullender</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 22:16:35 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csullender.com/tags/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hackintosh 2.0 Benchmark</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/hackintosh-2.0-benchmark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 21:37:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/hackintosh-2.0-benchmark/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since I am obsessed with quantifying things, I absolutely had to benchmark my &lt;a href="https://csullender.com/posts/hackintosh-2.0/" title="Hackintosh 2.0" >new Hackintosh rig&lt;/a> to see what my new purchases had afforded cost me. I ran a handful of different benchmarks under both OS X and Windows boots to see what the &lt;a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16819117372" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Intel Core i5-4690K&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16814487076" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EVGA GeForce GTX 970 SC&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16820147360" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Samsung 850 Pro&lt;/a> could do. So without further ado, here are the results of my benchmarks!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="Header.jpg" alt="Header">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="geekbenchhttpswwwgeekbenchcom">
 &lt;a href="https://www.geekbench.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Geekbench&lt;/a>
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#geekbenchhttpswwwgeekbenchcom">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Tested processor performance across &lt;a href="https://csullender.com/posts/the-hackintosh/" title="The Hackintosh" >Hackintosh v1.0&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://csullender.com/posts/hackintosh-2.0/" title="Hackintosh 2.0" >v2.0&lt;/a>, and a MacBook Pro (Early 2011, 15-inch). All tests were conducted 5 times and averaged together on OS X 10.10.1 Yosemite with no overclocking. While the i5-2500K (3.3GHz) in my original Hackintosh had similar performance to the i7-2720QM (2.2GHz) in the MacBook Pro, the i5-4690K (3.5GHz) offers all-around better performance. &lt;strong>Based on overall Geekbench scores, the Hackintosh v2.0 system is roughly 33% better than its predecessor.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hackintosh 2.0</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/hackintosh-2.0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 04:58:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/hackintosh-2.0/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been roughly two years since I built my &lt;a href="https://csullender.com/posts/the-hackintosh/" title="The Hackintosh" >original Hackintosh&lt;/a> desktop computer and I decided earlier this year that the time was ripe for an upgrade. After considerable waffling on the exact components to get, I finally settled on an relatively high-end build largely based on the &lt;a href="http://www.tonymacx86.com/building-customac-buyers-guide-december-2014.html" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">December CustoMac Buyer&amp;rsquo;s Guide&lt;/a> that reused a few components from my original Hackintosh (&lt;a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16811139008" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">case&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16817371031" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">power supply&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16820231429" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">memory&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="header.jpg" alt="Hackintosh 2.0 Header">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16813128707" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gigabyte GA-Z97X-UD5H&lt;/a> (Motherboard)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16819117372" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Intel Core i5-4690K&lt;/a> (CPU)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16814487076" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EVGA GeForce GTX 970 Superclocked&lt;/a> (GPU)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16820147360" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Samsung 850 Pro SSD 256GB&lt;/a> (SSD)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=9SIA1CZ1H27204" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TP-Link PCI Express Wifi Adapter&lt;/a> (WiFi)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The most difficult decision by far concerned the graphics card since the current generation &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/mac-pro/specs/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mac Pro&lt;/a> uses a custom AMD GPU whereas most Hackintosh guides recommend NVIDIA cards. Since there are currently no Macs with any of these NVIDIA cards, there is no native support for them in OS X. This obviously makes using them a little more difficult compared to my first build which basically worked out-of-box. After &lt;a href="http://www.tonymacx86.com/graphics/143435-nvidia-releases-alternate-graphics-drivers-10-10-0-343-01-01-maxwell-geforce-gtx-970-980-support.html" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">extensive research&lt;/a>, I decided on the &lt;a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16814487076" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GeForce GTX 970&lt;/a> since recently released &lt;a href="http://www.tonymacx86.com/graphics/155506-nvidia-releases-alternate-graphics-drivers-10-10-2-343-02-02-a.html" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">alternate drivers from NVIDIA&lt;/a> made the card viable on OS X 10.10 Yosemite without too much trouble.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prevent Bootcamp Partition from Mounting</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/prevent-bootcamp-partition-from-automatically-mounting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 04:34:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/prevent-bootcamp-partition-from-automatically-mounting/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re on a Mac with Windows installed via Bootcamp then you&amp;rsquo;ve no doubt noticed that the Bootcamp partition mounts as another drive when using OSX. I rarely needed access to the contents of my Bootcamp installation so I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be nice to prevent the partition from mounting at all on the Mac side of things. There&amp;rsquo;s a relatively easy way to achieve this using just a little bit of command line fiddling. The only thing you need is administrative rights on the computer. The first thing we need to know is the Universal Unique Identifier (UUID) of the Bootcamp partition that you want to prevent from automatically mounting. Open up the &lt;strong>Disk Utility&lt;/strong> application located in the Utilities folder of your Application folder. Locate the desired partition in the list on the left as shown below. In my case, the partition is called &amp;ldquo;Windows&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sad Mac: The Chronology of a Broken MacBook Pro</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/sad-mac/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 18:08:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/sad-mac/</guid><description>&lt;p>The following is a record of the problems I encountered with my MacBook Pro (Early 2011) beginning in late August and hopefully culminating in a once-again functional laptop. I&amp;rsquo;m making an effort to document all of the steps I took in attempting to rectify the situation including my experience with the Apple Retail Store. I&amp;rsquo;ve had great experiences with the repair team at Apple Stores in the past and I hope this will continue the trend.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting MATLAB to work on Mac OS X 10.8 'Mountain Lion'</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/getting-matlab-to-work-in-mountain-lion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 15:36:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/getting-matlab-to-work-in-mountain-lion/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the biggest risks of immediately upgrading to a new operating system is the loss of functionality for vital programs. While developers will scramble to get their apps ready for the sweeping changes oft accompanied by an upgrade to an operating system, it is inevitable that bugs/quirks/errors will surface. As an engineering graduate student, one of the programs I use quite frequently is &lt;a href="http://www.mathworks.com/products/matlab/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MATLAB&lt;/a>, which is built upon the X11 window system for the Apple OS environment. In the latest update to OS X, &lt;a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/HT5293" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple decided to remove X11&lt;/a> in favor of an open-source development called XQuartz. What this means is that if you upgrade to Mountain Lion, MATLAB cannot run because X11 is no longer included in the operating system. While I&amp;rsquo;m sure many will complain about Apple&amp;rsquo;s apparent lack of support for one of the most commonly used technical programs, they did not truly abandon X11. Rather, they have provided development support to the &lt;a href="http://xquartz.macosforge.org/landing/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">XQuartz project&lt;/a> which is effectively an updated version of X11 which was first included in Mac OS X 10.5.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Upgrading to Mountain Lion</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/upgrading-to-mountain-lion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 19:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/upgrading-to-mountain-lion/</guid><description>&lt;p>The release of the latest Apple computer operating system &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/osx/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OS X 10.8 &amp;lsquo;Mountain Lion&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a> has been a &lt;a href="http://www.engadget.com/2012/07/30/apple-reports-three-million-mountain-lion-downloads-in-four-days/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">resounding success&lt;/a> with over 3 million copies sold in less than four days. As with any system update, the Hackintosh community anxiously starts refreshing their favorite websites (&lt;a href="http://www.tonymacx86.com/home.php" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TonyMacx86&lt;/a>) in hopes of reading tales of successful installations before attempting it themselves. After installing the $20 update onto my laptop, I finally decided to give it a whirl on &lt;a href="http://www.csullender.com/blog/2012/02/12/the-hackintosh/" title="The Hackintosh" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">my Hackintosh.&lt;/a> I used the &lt;a href="http://www.tonymacx86.com/61-unibeast-1-5-install-os-x-mountain-lion-any-supported-intel-based-pc.html" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Unibeast&lt;/a> tool from the aforementioned &lt;a href="http://www.tonymacx86.com/home.php" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TonyMacx86&lt;/a> community to create a bootable flash drive with the Mountain Lion installer. A typical installation would then simply require booting off the flash drive, selecting the installation drive, and then enjoying the new OS. Unfortunately, my graphics card (ATI Radeon HD 6870) has had issues with the installation process and requires a few extra steps to get everything working. Without these additional modifications, the installer hangs at the launch screen indefinitely. This fix should work for any ATI Radeon 6XXX card but I have only tried it on the 6870.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Upgrades and Overclocks</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/upgrades-and-overclocks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 22:06:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/upgrades-and-overclocks/</guid><description>&lt;p>After about two months of using my new &lt;a href="http://www.csullender.com/blog/2012/02/12/the-hackintosh/" title="The Hackintosh" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hackintosh&lt;/a> without any custom modifications, I decided I wanted to overclock my 3.3GHz &lt;a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16819115072" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Intel Core i5-2500K&lt;/a> processor a little bit to see if I would notice a performance increase. However, in order to do this, the horribly inadequate stock Intel CPU cooler needed to be replaced. After a brief search online, I settled on the &lt;a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16835103065" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cooler Master Hyper 212+&lt;/a> as a suitable replacement for my CPU cooling needs. After an excruciating two-day wait, the part finally came in and I began the installation process of this gargantuan new cooling unit that just barely fit into my case. The new heatsink offered easily 10x more surface area for heat dissipation, which drastically increased the cooling efficiency of the running CPU. With the stock cooler, I saw the CPU idling around 45-50C. In stark contrast, the overclocked system now idles around 35C.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Hackintosh</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/the-hackintosh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 22:09:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/the-hackintosh/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the weeks leading up to my winter break from classes, I decided I was going to build a gaming computer since I was tired of playing on my laptop. While I was originally planning on just building a beastly Windows machine, I realized it was now ridiculously easy to throw together parts to make a &amp;ldquo;Hackintosh,&amp;rdquo; or a computer running Mac OS X minus the Apple hardware and price. I spent several weeks researching the viability of the Hackintosh build, predominately on &lt;a href="http://www.tonymacx86.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TonyMacX86&lt;/a>, and selecting the components for my system. I ended up settling on the following list of hardware, rocking a SSD for my operating system and a regular HD for everything else.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>