<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Photography on Colin Sullender</title><link>https://csullender.com/tags/photography/</link><description>Recent content in Photography on Colin Sullender</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 23:11:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csullender.com/tags/photography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Facebook Photo Compression</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/facebook-photo-compression/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 23:11:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/facebook-photo-compression/</guid><description>A couple weeks ago there was a Reddit post on /r/Android recommending Facebook users upload photos via the mobile website rather than the official Android Facebook app. The app reportedly compressed an original 8MP (4.5MB) photo to only 0.6MP (100kB) whereas the mobile website uploaded at 3MP (440kB). For a typical 4:3 ratio photograph, 0.6MP works out to neither dimension having more than 1000 pixels! Viewers on almost all current smartphones and tablets would be looking at an image smaller than their screen size.</description></item><item><title>SXSW 2015</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2015/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 02:26:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2015/</guid><description>Another year, another South By, another week of extensive walking and partaking in free parties and concerts. SXSW 2015 has truly turned Austin into a spring break for mid 20-year-olds. As usual, I always go in with zero expectations and just tried to have a good time.
The first big event was on Saturday at Amy Poehler&amp;rsquo;s Smart Girls Party at Banger&amp;rsquo;s Sausage House and Beer Garden which was also where Geek &amp;amp; Sundry and Tabletop had all-day events.</description></item><item><title>Oscar Party 8.0</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/oscar-party-8/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 03:47:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/oscar-party-8/</guid><description>Another year, another Oscar Party. The eighth installment of Peter Voyvodic&amp;rsquo;s celebration of the nominees for Academy Award for Best Picture was just as crazy and just as much fun as ever. There&amp;rsquo;s something exhilarating about cramming 50+ people into a tiny studio apartment and preparing an 8-dish offering. The menu and dishes are pictured below. For more behind-the-scenes photos, check out my Flickr album.
The Theory of Everything Pork belly with molasses and roasted potatoes with thyme in pea foam</description></item><item><title>MotoGP ATX 2014</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/motogp-atx-2014/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 01:28:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/motogp-atx-2014/</guid><description>The Red Bull Grand Prix of the Americas was this past weekend at the Circuit of the Americas in Austin, TX. The event spans three days with practice and qualifiers occurring on Saturday and the races for the three classes (MotoGP, Moto2, and Moto3) occurring on Sunday. I attended both days of weekend events and had a great time watching beastly motorcycles roar past Turn 1. I&amp;rsquo;ve included a selection of photos and videos below.</description></item><item><title>SXSW 2014</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 00:43:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/sxsw-2014/</guid><description>Another crazy SXSW has come and gone in Austin, TX, and I&amp;rsquo;m completely exhausted. Unlike the past two years where most of my participation was during the Music portion of the festival, I explored extensively during Interactive (i.e. earlier). The biggest events I attended were the Dropbox party and the multi-day Rachael Ray Feedback House Party. The first was at a brand new bar on Rainey Street called Container Bar and featured live music from Wild Cub (they&amp;rsquo;re gonna blow up).</description></item><item><title>#OscarMadness</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/oscarmadness/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 22:23:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/oscarmadness/</guid><description>For the past six years, my friend Peter Voyvodic has hosted an annual Oscar party where he serves up food inspired by each of the Academy Award for Best Picture Nominees. I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to attend the past two years (since I&amp;rsquo;ve been in Austin) and it has always been a blast. Last year I had a ton of fun assisting with the Sunday food preparation so I was anxious to help again this year.</description></item><item><title>Colorado Summer</title><link>https://csullender.com/posts/colorado-summer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 23:33:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csullender.com/posts/colorado-summer/</guid><description>I recently visited Estes Park, Colorado where my dad has moved/semi-retired and took a ton of pictures since it&amp;rsquo;s absolutely beautiful up there. Here are a select few with many more available on my Flickr account. Sadly there was almost no snow in the park, which is apparently very unusual (thanks a lot global warming). Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to visit again around Christmas so there should be plenty of that annoying white precipitation on the ground.</description></item></channel></rss>